《雷霆沙赞2：众神之怒》
传说告诉我们 只有少数勇士
The lore tells us of a valiant few.
能在战斗和迷雾之中屹立不倒
who stood above the fray and fog.
天哪 他们一定是用了什么大杀器
My, what weapons they must have wielded.
这就要说到我们的展品了
Which brings us to our current exhibit,
神话中的那根众神之杖
the mythical staff of the gods.
在荷马史诗中 这根神杖可以控制
In Homer's tale,
并使用众神的力量
the staff was said to harness the gift of all gods.
欢迎 光荣的士兵们
Oh. Welcome, proud soldiers.
我说过吧 博物馆充满乐趣
What did I say? Museums are fun.
是大脑的精神乐园
Amusement parks for the brains.
淡定 不要推推搡搡
Okay, there's no reason to get pushy.
每个人都有机会参观
Everyone will get a chance to see it.
它是用两千多年难得一见的心材雕刻而成的
Carved from a heartwood not seen in over 2, 000 years,
这件断成两截的古代制品
the two halves of this ancient replica were recently discovered in,
是不久前
of all places,
在费城郊外的一座废物处理厂偶然发现的
a waste processing plant outside of Philadelphia.
它非常坚硬 据说弄坏了三台垃圾压实机
So strong, they reportedly broke three trash compactors.
下面 朋友 不要乱动
Okay, um, friends, that's enough.
大家应该专心听我介绍 住手
I'm, I'm sort of the star of the show here… Stop!
住手 先生
Stop! Sir!
先生
Sir!
嘿 你们要干什么
Hey, what are you doing?
[咒语]
Unleash the chaos.
女士们 请放我走吧
Ladies, please just let me go.
[咒语]
博物馆确实非常有趣
Turns out museums are fun.
我们再玩玩别的
Let's have more of it.
神杖断成两截 我们什么都做不了
We can do nothing while the staff remains sundered.
人界继承者的数量远超我们
The champions of this realm outnumber us.
人类的继承者仍然是人类
Human champions are still humans.
而我们是神
and we are gods.
千万不要低估巫师的眼光和判断力
Do not underestimate the judgement of the wizard.
为了保护众神的力量
To protect the power of the gods,
他一定会以最严格的条件
he will have chosen with meticulous precision.
筛选出这个世界前所未见的最强大的
the strongest, most keenly intelligent champions.
最具智慧的神杖继承者
this realm has ever witnessed.
我就是个傻小子
I'm an idiot.
老实说 我不配拥有这些超能力
I don't deserve these powers, if I'm being honest.
我做什么贡献了
Like, what am I even contributing?
那个穿着红色战衣 绣着闪电的超级英雄
There's already a superhero with a red suit, with a lightning bolt on it and I'm fast,
速度比我还快呢
but he's faster.
还有海王那身腱子肉 一看就特别爷们儿
Aquaman is literally huge, and he's so manly.
蝙蝠侠也够酷 而我什么都不是
and Batman is so cool! And I'm just me.
这些话我没法跟人说
And I can't say this to anyone else,
因为家里人把我当领袖 可我觉得
'cause my family looks to me as a leader, but I feel like.
我是个假货
a fraud.
你知道我只是个儿科医生吧
You understand I'm a… pediatrician,
对吗
right?
我是说 另一个病人推荐我来找你
I mean, yeah, well, you were recommended by another patient,
叫比利巴特森 无所谓
Billy Batson. It doesn't matter.
你能帮我修复大脑
Can you help fix my thoughts so that.
让我不再产生那些想法吗
they just, like, you know, stop happening?
我再说一遍 我不是精神科医生
All right, look. And, again, pediatrician, not a psychiatrist,
不过 听上去你好像得了冒名顶替综合症
but it sounds to me like you're experiencing imposter syndrome.
通常 这种病症源于童年时期的创伤经历
And often, that originates from trauma early in life,
所以如果你不介意
so if you don't mind me asking,
童年的事你还记得清吗
how well do you remember your childhood?
仿佛今天的事
Like it was today.
创伤 不好说
Trauma? Uh, I don't know.
我从没见过父亲
I mean, I never met my dad.
妈妈在圣诞狂欢节抛弃了我
Uh, my mom abandoned me at a Christmas carnival.
我在寄养系统中辗转
I spent a lot of time in the foster system,
逃离了十一个家 打架无数
ran away from 11 homes, got into a lot of fights.
然后被一个巫师绑架 给了我超能力
Then I was abducted by a wizard who gave me superpowers.
然后那老兄就在我面前死了
and then dude just, like, died in front of my face.
这可不是小创伤
That's not a small amount.
一个博士召唤出七个恶魔 挟持了我全家
A doctor conjured seven demons and held my whole family hostage,
逼得我们挖了他一个眼球
so we had to rip out one of his eyeballs,
然后每个人都获得了超能力
and then everybody got superpowers,
现在他们各行其是
but now everyone's kind of, like, doing their own thing.
只有我拼命想把他们捏在一起
and I'm the only one trying to keep everybody together.
好吧 好吧 我们先处理好这些
Okay, okay. Well, let's just process that.
好吗 你先是被父母抛弃
Right? Rejected by your parents,
然后是寄养系统
then by the system,
现在又被你拼死保护的城市抛弃了
and now rejected by a city you try to protect.
我没说被我的城市抛弃了
I never said I was rejected by my city.
（被城市抛弃了）
《宾州论坛报》 被城市抛弃了
"Rejected by city."
- 那是《论坛报》 没人看《论坛报》 - 我看
- That's the Tribune. Nobody reads the Tribune. - I do.
好吧 好吧
Anyway, okay, well, um…
我要感谢你的帮助
I, uh, appreciate your help,
（达里奥巴瓦医师）
但是我得去解决现实问题了
but I got some real problems.
恐怖分子劫持了一些人质 所以
There's this terrorist hostage situation going on, so…
- 劫持了人质 - 对
- Hostage situation? - Yeah.
（人质被杀 任务失败 再试一次）
我打得太烂了
I suck balls at this.
为什么老打战争游戏
Why do we always have to play war games?
嘿 这是为其他工作练习
Hey, it's practice for our other job.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
军事策略 多队员协作
Military strategy, multiple team members,
人人都有特殊技能 攻击未知的敌人
each with a special skillset unleashed against an unknown enemy.
我知道这很荒谬
I know how it sounds,
可房子总是被闪电击中 不骗你
but the house keeps getting struck by lightning, Leo. I'm telling you.
而且 你总是强调要团队合作
Besides, you're the one always talking about teamwork.
但是我们不需要枪
But we don't need guns!
达拉
Darla?
就是这个 这可是大新闻
This is it. This is big time.
我们就是枪
We are the guns.
达拉
Darla!
我兜里怎么有彩虹糖
Why were there Skittles in my pockets?
原本想给你个惊喜的
It was supposed to be a surprise.
是惊吓
It was.
她最近脾气很差
Hmm, she's very moody lately.
所以我才给她彩虹糖的
Why do you think I put Skittles in her pocket?
好球
Ole.
这就是阻退成吉思汗的独角兽吗
Is this an army of unicorns killing Genghis Khan?
是的
Yes.
独角兽并不存在
Unicorns aren't real.
这叫思辨历史 尤金 去查查
It's called speculative history, Eugene. Look it up.
比利 你别走啊 角色会死的
Billy, you can't just leave. Your guy's gonna die!
- 看见了 - 是的
- See? - Yes.
我说过 你看了就会迷上它
I told you you would get into it if you gave it a chance.
是的 我感受到魅力了
Yeah, I'm really starting to see the appeal.
（马塞尔韦德 外场手 我们热爱费城 费城人队）
出了什么事
What's going on?
喂 你干什么
Dude, what are you doing?
有可能发生紧急事件
Possible 10-99 in progress.
通报多起道路开裂报告
Multiple reports of cracking on roadway.
桥梁悬索受损
Fraying suspension cables.
所有单位前往本富兰克林大桥
All units to the Ben Franklin Bridge.
好了
Yeah.
音乐太疯狂了
It's crazy music, Freddy.
可不是 而且 主旋律非常紧张
It is, isn't it? Very urgent melody to it.
我们应该去看现场
We should see it performed live.
我也这么想 我们能弄到门票
I was thinking the same thing. I feel like we can get tickets to that concert.
两张 也许不用 六张
Two. Maybe not six.
同进同退 这是规矩
All or none. That's the rule.
行 还是老规矩
Yet I'm still gonna walk backwards now.
我倒退出去 所以 这是你最后的机会
So, now's your last and final chance.
比利巴特森 跟我走 不不不
Billy Batson, come with me. No, no, no!
今天费城的天气真好 谁想跟我去转转
Man, it sure is a beautiful day in Philadelphia!
真的吗
Is it though?
- 我快好了 - 又来
- Almost finished. - Again?
- 好吧 - 最好是好事
- Okay. - This better be good.
喂喂 你们去哪儿
Whoa, whoa! Where's everyone going?
去打击犯罪
To fight crime?
好的
Okay.
- 再见 妈妈 - 再见 妈妈
- Bye, Mom. - Bye, Mom.
- 再见 - 再见 罗莎
- Bye. - Bye, Rosa.
耐心点
Give it time.
好了吗
You guys ready?
沙赞
Shazam!
（卡特里托斯椒盐卷饼）
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
桥要断了
It's gonna break!
快跑
Run!
∮ 我渴望一位英雄 ∮
∮ I need a hero ∮
∮ 我痴痴地等待英雄 直至长夜渐尽 ∮
∮ I'm holding out for a hero Till the end of the night ∮
∮ 他强壮有力 他身手敏捷 ∮
∮ He's gotta be strong, and he's gotta be fast ∮
∮ 他要刚刚战斗归来 ∮
∮ And he's gotta be fresh from the fight ∮
∮ 我渴望一位英雄 ∮
∮ I need a hero ∮
不要
No, no, no.
好了 闭嘴吧
No way, shut up! Did I just save you.
听这首歌的时候我救过你吗
while you were listening to this song?
别叫 我马上
No! I got you, I got you.
无需恐慌 全能大队长在此
No need to panic. Captain Everypower is here.
开个玩笑 小事一桩
I'm just kidding, it's real easy.
嗨
Hi!
天哪 有小猫咪
Oh, my gosh. Kittens!
它们真可爱
Oh! They're so cute!
丢下我们不管了
Did she just leave us?
好了 我们走了
Okay, let's go.
（限速 谢谢）
（水族馆 卡姆登海滨）
- 好了 - 不 我来扶你
- Okay. - No, no, no, I got ya!
那是我的跟班 全能小队长
That's my sidekick. Captain Everypower Junior.
什么 小队长
Hey! Junior?
你们可要抱紧了
You're gonna wanna hold on tight.
大家都安全了
Everyone's safe.
干得好 玛丽 全家集合了
Awesome job, Mary. Circle up, fam!
好了 情况是这样的
All right, here's the situation.
我们还有一件事要做
We have one more job to do.
尽量阻止这座桥坍塌
and that's to keep this bridge from collapsing.
本富兰克林大桥坍塌了
The Ben Franklin Bridge has collapsed.
好在没有人员伤亡
Fortunately, there are no casualties.
这要归功于我们的英雄们 这是其中一位
Thanks in part to our local heroes, one with me now.
（14新闻频道 费城焦点栏目 突发新闻 本富兰克林大桥坍塌了）
很荣幸 南希 怎么说呢
It's great to be here, Nancy. What can I say?
这都是日常工作
It's all in a day's work.
有人说你们是费城的废柴 你有何感想
Right. Well, how do you feel about being dubbed the Philadelphia Fiascoes?
这不是官方称号
Given that that's not an official title,
我们无所谓 那不是我们的称号
we feel nothing about it. That is not our name.
对 重要的是群众都平安无事
Right, but the important thing is…
这些人怎么回事
What is wrong with these people?
你有没有…
Have you ever no…
我去看看孩子们
I'm gonna go check on the kids.
没错 天知道他们在干什么
Yeah, you should. God only knows what they're up to.
可能在吸毒 或是在TikTok抽电子烟
Probably drugs, right? Probably taking selfies while vaping on TikTok.
那是小猫吗
Is that a kitten?
不是
No.
（大桥坍塌 当地超级英雄团救了人 毁了大桥）
（基地）
（韦恩 暴食）
（温馨的家）
我想叫你唐尼
I'm gonna name you Tawny.
（有机化学）
毁了大桥 什么
"Destroy bridge"? What?
没保住跟毁是两码事 对不对
Not saving is different than breaking. Am I wrong?
而且我们救的人 数都数不过来
Am I wrong about this? Also, we saved countless lives.
162个人 是有数的
A hundred sixty-two. It's countable.
恩情是无法计算的 玛丽
Emotionally countless, Mary.
尤金呢
Where's Eugene?
跟平时一样 在绘制密室门地形图
Where he always is. Mapping out the Room of Doors.
尤金
Eugene!
嘿 老弟 你在哪儿
Hey, buddy! Where you at?
（小心蜘蛛狗 青少年期）
嘿 尤金
Hey, Eugene.
（仙境 所有人 安全）
你在哪儿 我们要开会了 尤金 喂
Hello? We have a meeting, Eugene.
你迟到了
You're late.
千万不要进去
Do not go in there.
（噩梦燃料 成熟期）
好了 家庭成员们 开始吧
All right, fam-jam, let's jump in.
（重点回顾）
好 有功 也有过
All right, big day, big bridge,
犯了几个错误 我们要反思这些错误
kind of a couple blunders, right? But we're gonna meditate on those mistakes right now.
玛丽
Mary?
我正在思考有机化学
Organic chem is my meditation.
难怪你没有什么朋友 这很正常
Said nobody with friends ever, really.
事实上 如果上了大学 我就会有朋友
In point of fact, I'd have friends if I had gone to college.
事实上
In point of fact.
是不需要上大学的聪明人挂在嘴上的聪明话
is exactly the kind of smart thing that a smart person who doesn't need to go to college says.
所以 我们继续看回放
So, let's go back to the tape.
好 伙计们 看见吗
Now, guys, as you can see,
我们一出场就非常非常有气势 对吧
we started off real, real, real, real strong, right?
总之 有凝聚力 有激情 非常棒
Right up top, all that cohesiveness, energy, terrific!
抱歉教练 我得去飞飞
Oh, sorry, Coach. Gotta fly IRL.
不行 我还没完呢
No, no, no, I'm not done with the presentation.
我知道 我喜欢你的每日回顾
I know. And I love these daily recaps.
可是晚饭前我得飞飞 松松筋骨
I just gotta spread my wings a bit before dinner. It helps keep me loose!
好好 不回顾了
Okay, fine, fine. No recap.
等会儿我们一起去 好不好
We'll go have a group hang in the air. That sounds great.
我得去测一下这种粘液的毒性
I gotta test this slime for toxicity.
我有刺痛感了
'cause I'm starting to… tingle.
费城人队的比赛刚开始
Oh. The, uh, Phillies game just came on.
所以我该去看棒球比赛
so I'm gonna go ahead and, uh, watch baseball.
我得把唐尼送回去了
It's right that I give Tawny back.
拜托 怎么回事
Oh, come on! What is happening?
怎么都这样 我们要同进同退
What is happening right now? All or none, guys!
- 别说你得工作… - 我确实得工作
- If you say you have to work… - I have to work.
工作 你为什么要工作
Why do you even have a job?
神奇女侠就没工作
Wonder Woman doesn't have a job!
够了
Stop.
真的 你觉得她扎个马尾
No, seriously. Do you think she wears a ponytail and glasses…
戴个眼镜就没人认识她
and, like, nobody recognizes her…
- 然后就能当个会计 - 别说了
- and she's, like, an accountant or something? - Just stop.
是你把他们抓得太紧了
You are holding on too tight.
弗莱迪只是想单独飞行十分钟
Just 'cause Freddy wants to fly solo for ten minutes.
他不会像你妈妈一样抛弃你
doesn't mean he's gonna leave you like your mom.
而我 只是想上大学 不是要抛弃家人
Or me wanting to go to college means I'm abandoning the family.
又来了 又是大学的话题
Oh. Okay, cool, it's about college again.
我真是服了你
I totally get it.
你真的没想过自己吗
Yeah. Do you really not see yourself?
再过五个月你就18了
You turn 18 in five months.
他们不会赶我走 你也没被赶走
They're not gonna kick me out. They didn't kick you out.
维克多和罗莎都是好人
Victor and Rosa are saints, yes,
可你即将超过寄养年龄 就像我一样
but you're about to age out of the foster system just like I did.
是是 我知道 我了解这个体系
Yeah, I get it. I know how it works, okay?
真的
Do you?
维克多和罗莎快交不起房租了
Victor and Rosa can barely pay rent.
州政府不再寄给我负担食宿的支票了
And the state no longer sends checks to feed or house me.
很快你也收不到了
and soon there will be no checks for you.
我不管神奇女侠是否工作
I don't care if Wonder Woman has a job.
我想出份力 跟所有人一样
I want to contribute. At some point,
我们必须找份工作
Billy, like everyone on Earth, we have to get a job or…
或是离开家
leave home.
没有永恒不变
Nothing lasts forever.
可是 这地方就叫永恒之岩
I mean, it's literally called the Rock of Eternity.
有些东西是可以永恒不变的
So, clearly, some things do last forever.
让我安静地等死吧
Leave me to die.
我们带来了一件礼物
Oh, but we come bearing gifts.
是魔法 这不可能
Magic. Impossible.
这个世界不能使用魔法
This realm was sealed off from magic.
是的 是你把魔法夺走了 包括我父亲的
Yes. After you ripped it from our father's very core.
还有这个世界众神的
From every god in this realm.
还有我的
From me.
你不记得夺走了哪些吗
Do you not remember what you took?
忘了我的特殊能力是什么吗
What my particular power was?
- 我拥有大自然的力量 - 不
- The power of elements. - No.
我设置了一道屏障
I cast a barrier to prevent your kind.
阻止你们这些神进入人界
from entering the human realm.
屏障消失的唯一原因 只可能是
The only way that barrier could be removed is if…
这个东西断了
Someone broke this?
怎么可能 继承者在哪儿
How did… Where is the Champion?
这是你亲手为我们的父亲炼造的神杖
It was your hands that forged this staff for our father.
只有你的力量能修复它
and yours that will mend it.
我说过 宁死也不会帮助你们
I told you I would die before I help you.
现在 说出那个词
Now, say the word.
休想
Never. Never!
不要把话说绝了
Never say never.
说出那个词
Say the word.
沙赞
Shazam!
我们可以好好玩了
Now we get to have our fun.
小孩子才贪玩 亲爱的 而我们是在打仗
Fun is for children, dear. We are at war.
- 天哪 对不起 - 对不起
- Oh, my gosh. - Oh, my goodness. - I am so sorry! - I'm so sorry!
不 别道歉 是我不好
No, don't be sorry. I'm sorry!
是我不好 你没事吧
No, it's totally my fault. Are you okay?
- 我没事 - 那就好 - 我一直很好
- I'm okay, yeah. - Okay, yeah. - I'm always okay.
对了 你知道这地方在哪儿吗
Good. Uh, actually, do you… do you know where this is?
桑德斯小姐 是的 我当然知道
Miss Saunders! Yeah, absolutely.
我刚才破音了 所以怪怪的
is what I meant to say. Voice crack. It's weird.
不用担心
Oh, no, no worries. If it makes you feel any better.
你感觉好就行 你现在脸红得厉害
it's nothing compared to the amount that you're blushing right now.
我一自信就脸红
Oh, I blush when I'm confident.
她在这儿呢
There she is.
- 新来的 第一堂课 - 对
- New girl. First period. - Yeah.
我叫布雷特 这是伯克
I'm Brett. This is Burke.
不管你需要什么 就来找我们
Listen, if you need anything at all, we're your guys.
我们全有
We got it.
布莱耶兄弟 真的什么都有
Brett and Burke Breyer. They got it all.
自恋型人格障碍 衣原体
I mean, what is it, narcissistic personality disorder, chlamydia, they got it.
他们都有 而且多到数不清
Plenty of it to go around, too.
这位 霹雳咔嚓侠许愿小子
This is Thundercrack's Make-A-Wish kid.
自己觉得是个人物
Fanboy here thinks he's a big boy now.
不知道属于哪儿
Yeah, he doesn't know where he belongs.
我知道 我不属于那个垃圾桶
Sure I do. I don't belong in that trash can.
全是一股人渣味
'Cause that's… I'll smell like human garbage,
闻到吗 你们独有的味
do you realize that? And that's your brand, guys!
弗里曼倒下了
Down goes Freeman.
嘿 看着
Hey, hey! Look!
- 现在我是超级英雄了 - 可以
- Now I'm a superhero. - Nice!
这东西怎么在这儿
What is this thing doing here?
校工干的
Janitors.
- 起来 你在做什么 - 起来
- Get up, man. What are you doin'? - Come on.
你自己会修好吧
You're gonna want to get this fixed, huh?
- 是啊 因为它你才跌倒的 - 对
- Yeah, that's probably why you fell. - Yeah.
再见 新来的
Bye, new girl.
- 谢谢你 盖可先生 - 别客气
- Jeez, thanks Mr. Geckle. - Don't sweat it.
以前那个垃圾桶就像我的第二个家
That trash can was like a second home to me when I went here.
明知道他们会打你 你还多管闲事
Hey. You knew those guys were gonna hit you, but you stepped in anyway.
那是我自娱自乐的方式
You know something? That's how I amuse myself.
我越搞笑
The funnier I am,
就被打得越惨
the more I get punched.
我轻松多了
Well, it made me laugh.
所以
So…
英雄
Hero.
你能送我去上课吗
You gonna walk me to class, or what?
为什么送你去上课 为什么 好的
Why would I… Walk you to class? No. Why would I wanna do that? Yes!
谢谢
Thanks.
那 从头说吧
So, from the top.
霹雳咔嚓侠许愿小子是怎么回事
What is Thundercrack's Make-A-Wish kid?
这个 这是个内部梗 简单来说
Yeah. Um, it's real inside baseball, but basically,
不久前我碰巧和几个超级英雄
a while ago I happened to have some lunch.
在自助食堂吃了顿午饭
in the cafeteria with a few superheroes.
等等
Wait,
那个和超级英雄交朋友的孩子 就是你
the kid who's friends with superheroes. That was you?
- 是的 - 那他们还整你
- Yeah. - And they're still dicks to you?
可惜 你认识酷哥 不代表你就是酷哥
Sadly, just 'cause you know someone cool, doesn't really necessarily make you cool.
我觉得你挺酷的
You seem pretty cool to me.
弗莱迪
Freddy!
（烹饪艺术课）
是我的名字
Is my name.
抱歉 我喊得很突然 很大声
Sorry, that was weird and loud.
我叫弗莱迪 这是用正常声音说的
I'm Freddy, he said in a normal voice.
我叫安
I'm Anne.
安
Anne.
- 厉害 - 正中目标
- Nice! - Bullseye.
你应该把拐杖修好
Hey, you gotta fix that crutch, bro!
看什么
What?
[咒语]
很好 小家伙
Good, little one.
做得好
Well done.
去找到那个应该承担责任的
Now go find me the one responsible for this.
你这么想我很荣幸
I'm flattered that you feel this way.
真的 我的意思是说看看这一切
Truly, I mean, you know, like, look at all this, you know…
浪漫的环境
Romantic setting.
昂贵的香槟 大盘子小点心
and fancy champagne, big plates, tiny food.
可以说诚意十足
I mean, you went all out.
我很喜欢 真的 只是
I love that, I, I, I, I do.
我不确定是否做好了接受的准备
I'm just not sure that I'm really ready to commit right now, you know.
喂 等等 不是你不好
Wait, wait, wait. No, this isn't about you.
我保证 不是你不好 好吗 其实
I promise this is not about you. Okay? Look…
我知道全世界都希望我们俩在一起
I know the whole world wants to see this happen. You and me.
组个活力双雄 风情侠侣
The dynamic duo. The hottie goddies.
神赞双侠
She-zam.
或许我只是没有信心 害怕他们失望
I guess I'm just afraid that I'm… gonna let 'em all down.
还有
You know?
害怕让你失望
That I'm gonna let you down.
管这么多呢 我们试试
You know what? Screw it. Let's try.
疯狂地试一次 也许我们
Let's try this crazy thing. Maybe we'll, uh…
一吻就定情了
seal it with a kiss?
比利巴特森 你这个继承者是个大傻瓜
Billy Batson! You are a fool of a champion.
我的天 怎么回事
What the hell… What the hell is going on?
她的漂亮脸蛋呢 你不是已经死了吗
What happened to her beautiful face? Also, aren't you, like, dead-ass dead?
我来传达遥远世界的警告
I bring a warning from beyond your realm.
阿特拉斯的女儿们要来了
The daughters of Atlas are coming for you.
阿特拉斯的女儿们
Daughters of Atlas?
她们要毁掉你们的世界
They're coming to unmake your world.
让你们永生永世 遭受无穷无尽的折磨
and torture mankind for all eternity in the Pit of Endless Agony.
也许我应该把这些写下来
Okay, I feel like maybe I should be writing all this down.
- 安静 - 好的
- Quiet! - Okay, okay.
都是你干的好事
You don't know what you've done.
我真后悔当初选择了你
I regret ever choosing you.
因为你 隔离两个世界的屏障被打破了
Because of you, the barrier between the world has been brought down.
现在她们要来对付你 对付你的家人了
They will be hunting for you now. Hunting your family.
她们来了
Oh, they're coming.
听我说 比利
Listen to me, Billy.
你们的世界危在旦夕
The fate of your world depends on it.
有一件事你绝对不能让阿特拉斯的女儿们得逞
One thing you absolutely must not allow the daughters of Atlas.
那就是
to do is…
嘿 弗莱迪
Hey, Freddy?
不要 没意思 干过了
Nope, over it. Done it.
支票欺诈 胡扯什么
Check fraud? What, are you kidding me?
装甲车劫案 手到擒来呀
Armored car heist? I think I got that in the bag.
（蓄意破坏 野兽男孩）
沙赞
Shazam!
祝你好胃口
Bon appetit.
- 嗨 - 嗨 你好 你来了
- Hi. - Oh, hi! Yes, I mean, hi.
嗨 你想带我去那天坐的座位吗
Hi. Um, you wanna show me where you were sitting when it happened?
- 当然 当然可以 - 来 跟我来 - 好的
- Oh, yeah, of course. Totally. - Yeah. Follow me. - Okay, yeah.
就是 就是最后面那张桌子
So, basically, it's a table down at the end.
当时 当时我就坐在这儿
So I was sitting, yeah… Basically, I was sitting right here,
他坐在你那儿
and he was sitting right there.
- 这儿 - 是的
- Here? - Right there, yeah.
抱歉 是我的霸道哥哥
Oh, sorry. Overbearing brother.
我姐姐也是一样
Oh, I have one of those. Uh, a sister.
总是问我在哪儿
Always has to know where I am.
是吗 我太理解了
Right. I feel that, clearly.
还总觉得她更懂
Always thinks she knows better, too.
- 即便事实证明并非如此 - 没错
- Even when it's been factually proven otherwise? - Exactly.
不是我不爱她
And it's not that I don't love her.
只要不是 咄咄逼人
No, of course. It'd just be nice not to have someone…
事事都要盯着你
Constantly breathing down your neck.
只要你一睁眼
From the moment you wake up!
我不是小孩子了
'Cause I'm not a kid anymore.
就是 就比他小一个月 正好一个月
No! I'm a month younger, one month exactly.
做什么都要在一起吗
And do we have to do every single thing together?
- 不是 - 不是
- No! - No!
哦 比利 是你 这么巧
Oh! Billy! What… What a coinkidink!
我正跟我的朋友 安 说你有多好
I was just telling my friend Anne what a great guy you are.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
谈谈谈 他就喜欢谈 然后说个不停
We need to talk. This guy loves to talk. He's a great talker.
弗莱迪
Freddy.
- 我先去 马上回来 - 好的
- I have to talk to him. I'll be right back. - Okay.
你不是说巫师解体了吗
Wait, didn't you tell us the wizard disintegrated?
皮肤剥落了 变成了一堆粉末 就这样
The skin peeled off his face. He turned into a literal pile of ash. Yeah, seems definitive.
应该死透了
I dunno.
是啊 可是 在我的梦里
Yeah. Except now he's in my dreams.
他向我传递信息
and, Freddy, he's trying to give me a message.
这是星体投影能力
Could be astral projection powers.
那是什么
What's that?
像欧比旺克诺比死后连线你
Obi-Wan Kenobi-ing you from the great beyond?
- 好吧 放学后召开紧急会议 - 你也去
- That's it, I'm calling an emergency meeting after school. - I want you there.
我能去哪儿
Where else am I gonna go?
- 什么 - 老弟
- What? - Dude.
（全能大队长炸毁装甲卡车）
好吧 首先 那不是我炸毁的
Okay, first of all, I didn't explode it!
我到的时候已经炸了 那是什么 《论坛报》
All right? It was already like that and, and, and… What is that, the Tribune?
- 那是假新闻 - 弗莱迪 我们只有一个规矩
- It's fake news! - Freddy, we only have one rule.
- 同进同退 - 同进同退
- All or none. - All or none.
这个规矩很烂
And it's a stupid rule,
还有 有个女生愿意跟我聊天 比利
by the way. I have a girl talking to me, Billy.
女生啊 平生第一次
A girl. For the first time in my life!
我跟她也许没有结果
And I probably don't have a shot in hell with this girl,
可是 如果你继续控制我
but I'll never find out.
我永远不知道有没有戏
if you keep trying to control everything I wanna do!
- 记得来开会 弗莱迪 - 好的
- Just be at the Rock, Freddy. - Okay.
对了 她有个姐姐 也是个控制狂
By the way, uh, she has a sister. Total control freak.
你们一定合得来 没准还会爱上她
I think you guys would get along. Think you'd love her, actually.
真的 家人们 我知道这很疯狂
Look, look, look. Fam, I know it sounds crazy.
而且显然
And, and obviously.
我不知道那些话到底意味着什么
I don't know exactly what this all means.
但是他非常凶 声音很大
but, but he was super aggro and super loud.
我认为他想警告我们
and he was trying to warn us, I think.
乱七八糟说了一大堆巫师 神杖什么的
He was yelling about all this wizard-y mumbo-jumbo about realms and stuff.
你有必要这么大嗓门吗
Do you have to talk so loud?
是的 玛丽 跟他比差远了
Yeah, Mary, 'cause this is not that loud.
我认为这个音量在室内是可以接受的
I think this is a perfectly acceptable indoor voice volume.
- 怎么了 你还好吗 - 好
- What is the deal? Are you okay? - Yeah.
你为什么戴着墨镜
Why do you have sunglasses on?
早上去看眼科医生了
Did you go to the eye doctor this morning?
不知道 看起来确实去看眼科医生了
I dunno, it looks to me like Mary did go to the eye doctor,
不过她昨晚确实玩得很尽兴
but it was last night, and she had a lot of fun.
凭心而论 我确实很开心
In point of fact, I did have a great time.
我遇到了我的同龄人 我觉得很投缘
I met other people my age and I enjoyed myself.
你在眼科医生那儿交到了朋友
You made friends at the eye doctor?
不 她…
No, she…
对 言归正传 听着 他一直吼我
Yeah, can we get back on track? Listen, he's yelling at me.
说 阿特拉斯的女儿们要来对付我们
and he's saying the daughters of Atlas are coming to hunt us.
听我给你们念
So, check out what I found.
阿特拉斯的女儿们是泰坦阿特拉斯的后代
The daughters of Atlas are the offspring of the Titan Atlas…
都是废话
which is obvious,
她们的母亲 倪克斯 则是黑夜与死亡之神
but also Nyx, the Goddess of Night and Death.
晚上也有好事发生啊
Well, good things can happen at night.
与死亡
And death.
给我看看手机
Let me see this.
“女儿们守护着神话中的生命之树
"The daughters guard the mythic Tree of Life.
树上结出的金苹果
which grows golden apples that contain the seeds of life.
含有能孕育他们神界的生命之籽
which gave birth to their realm.
守护它的是一条龙”
protected by a… dragon."
打住
Hey, now.
我突然精神了
And I am suddenly here for this.
是这样吧
I know, right?
- 本来挺可怕的一件事 - 没想到还有龙 - 还有龙
- 'Cause, like, on one hand, totally terrifying. - On the other hand, dragon! - Dragon!
玛丽 我们怎么办
Mary. What are we doin'?
我不知道 老弟 这是你的会议
I don't know, man. This is your meeting.
对 没错 可我们得达成共识
Right, yes, fine, but we all need to be on the same page.
而且说实话 我一直觉得你们比我更聪明
and, and, and look, I often think that you think better than me.
巫师没有给我一个详细的教程 对吗
The wizard did not exactly give me a tutorial here, guys, okay?
这儿的很多东西我也不懂
Like, I don't know how a lot of this stuff works.
包括那些密室门
That, that room of doors,
一直燃烧的小提琴
or that violin that is, like, constantly burning which is super weird.
好奇怪 能让基地保持温度 对吗
but also definitely keeps the lair cozy, right?
他甚至没告诉我应该叫什么名字
He didn't even tell me my superhero name.
我不是没有努力
And it's not like I'm not tryin'.
我真的需要大家帮助
But I really, really need your help.
我认识个人 也许能帮上忙
Uh, I might know somebody that can help.
闭嘴 这东西能亮吗
Shut up. That lights up?
我的天哪
Shut up.
我忙着绘制整个基地的地形 你却瞒着我们
So, I'm mapping out the entire lair and you withhold this?
我们都被蒙在鼓里了 你可真行
And you have really been holding out on us. Jeez Louise, dude.
哇
Whoa!
- 哇什么 怎么了 - 快看
- "Whoa" what? "Whoa" what? - Look!
嘿 史蒂夫
Hey, Steve.
什么 你管它叫史蒂夫
What? You call the pen "Steve"?
对 跟它很配
Yeah, I thought he looked like a "Steve."
确实挺斯文的
He totally looks like a "Steve".
（罪与罚》读书报告 作者 佩德罗佩尼亚）
《罪与罚》的读书报告
"Crime and Punishment", a book report.
- 作者佩德罗佩尼亚 - 是
- "by Pedro Pena?" - Yeah.
佩德罗
Pedro.
老弟 这是作弊
Dude, that's cheating.
它什么都知道
I mean, he knows everything.
不信你问它
Seriously. Ask him.
问什么都行
You can just ask him stuff?
什么都行
Pretty much.
这么拽 厉害呀
Slick. Okay, cool.
史蒂夫 我们想找一些有关
Steve, we're looking for information.
阿特拉斯女儿们的资料
about the daughters of Atlas.
你能帮个忙吗
Can you please help us with that?
（希腊叛乱》第三卷）
（巫师理事会）
（凡人的审判）
（神谱》第七卷）
（神界的植物和动物）
这些都是书名
These are book titles.
好吧 我们去找找这些书
Okay. Let's just all pick a book, or something.
弗莱迪呢
Where's Freddy?
晦涩的神秘学 绝对是他擅长的
I mean, obscure mythology? Definitely his thing.
我已经不确定
I'm not even sure.
弗莱迪还知不知道他擅长什么了
Freddy knows what his thing is anymore.
（神界的植物和动物）
我从来没上来过
You know I've actually never, never been up here.
别撒谎
Don't lie.
这是你跟超级英雄聚会的地方 对吧
This is where you hang out with your superhero friends, isn't it?
不是 他们来这儿干什么 没事干了
No, actually, why would they ever have to… Why would they ever come here?
他们来过 是的 是那样
I mean they have, yes, they've driven by…
你真的认识他们吗
Do you actually know those guys?
还是杜撰出来的加拿大女友
Or is this like a "Canadian girlfriend" situation?
你说柯莱特吗 我和她还没确定关系呢
Oh, you mean Collette? Well, she and I aren't really exclusive, as of now.
你想见一个吗
Do you wanna meet one of them?
怎么个见法
Meet, like how?
面对面 就现在
Like, face-to-face, right now.
我就当你同意了
I'm gonna take that as a yes.
今天是你的幸运日 我打给最性感的那个
And today is your lucky day, because I'm gonna call the hot one.
她
Her?
- 不 性感的男人 - 他
- No, the male hot one. - Him?
- 不是吗 - 这是很主观的 对吧
- What? Him? - Look, I mean, it's all subjective, right?
但是全能大队长更受网民关注
But, um… Captain Everypower usually tops most online polls.
所以没事的
so… It's no big deal.
这是玩笑吗 弗莱迪
Is this a joke, Freddy?
因为我并不是要你证明什么 真的
'Cause I didn't mean to make you actually prove it, really.
不 这不是玩笑
No, it's not a joke.
我这就给他打电话 现在就打 别走
And I'm gonna call him right now. I'm gonna call him right now.
你待在这儿
So, don't move. So, stay right there.
嘿 全能大队长 你好
Hey, Captain Everypower. What's goin' on?
我是弗莱迪 对
It's your boy Freddy. Yeah.
上次我救过你的命
Remember that time I saved your life?
不 是另一次 对 还我个人情
No, no, no, the other time. Yeah. Well, I'm calling in that favor.
你就是安吧
You must be Anne.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
弗莱迪说你们是朋友
Friend of Freddy's, I hear.
是的 我们是朋友 你怎么…
I am, actually. Yeah. How are you…
我是因为拥有超能力
You know, I may be the one with the superpowers,
但是那个孩子 他是真正的英雄
but that kid, he's the real hero.
是的 说实话 我从没见过他那样的人
Yeah. I mean, honestly, I've never met anyone like him.
他很真诚 很温暖 很有趣
He's… genuine and warm and funny.
- 你夸了好多优点 - 是的
- That's a lot of nice things. - Yeah.
- 你们怎么认识的 - 在漫展上
- How did you two meet? - Comic Con.
- 什么是漫展 - 什么
- What's Comic Con? - What?
这本书上说 众神只把人类当成奴仆
According to this, gods considered humans servants,
供他们玩弄的玩具 该受罚的孩子
toys to be played with, children to be punished.
谢谢 史蒂夫
Thanks, Steve.
直到叛乱发生 人类开始反抗众神
Until the rebellion when the humans turned on the gods.
我正好读到这儿
I'm reading about that right now.
所以很显然
So, apparently,
这一切围绕一种强大的武器展开
all of this revolves around a powerful weapon.
阿特拉斯
So Atlas, uh,
也就是阿特拉斯女儿们的父亲 很明显
the father of the daughters of Atlas, obviously, yeah,
他用生命之树制作了一根神杖
he crafted a quarterstaff from the Tree of Life.
并用那根神杖将力量赋予某些神
and he used that staff to give powers to certain deities.
但是 也能用来夺走其他神的力量
but also to take powers away from others.
所以这根神杖里
So, the staff's where.
保存了阿特拉斯所有的超能力
Atlas stored all supernatural power.
对 说得没错 就像一块
Yes, exactly. It's like a,
储存魔法的电池
a battery for magic.
但是后来发生了变故
But when things got bad,
人类巫师理事会的成员联合起来
a council of human wizards got together.
从阿特拉斯那里偷走了神杖
and they stole the staff from Atlas.
并用它夺走了他的力量
And they used that to take his powers away.
有了他的魔法 他们又向其他神下手
And once they had his magic they went after other gods…
是那个巫师 我认识他 我认识这个巫师
Guys, that's the wizard! I know this guy, this is the wizard that I know!
这写的是什么
What do these say?
“所罗门的智慧 海格力斯的力量
"The Wisdom of Solomon,
阿特拉斯的毅力 宙斯的威力
Strength of Hercules, Stamina of Atlas,
阿基里斯的勇气 墨丘利的神速”
Power of Zeus, Courage of Achilles,
他们窃取了这些力量
Speed of Mercury." These are the powers they stole.
不
No.
（所罗门的智慧 海格力斯的力量 阿特拉斯的毅力 宙斯的威力 阿基里斯的勇气 墨丘利的神速）
原来沙赞是这个意思
Whoa, guys, look! This is what the name means.
这可比我想的酷多了
Which is way cooler than what I thought it was,
以前我还觉得有点儿掉价呢
which is just a bunch of hot garbage, so.
恕我直言
If I may point out.
其中一个超能力可能下落不明
one of the powers that may be possibly MIA.
（所罗门的智慧 海格力斯的力量）
抱歉 你真是毫不委婉
I'm sorry, are you very unsubtly implying.
非常直接地暗示我缺乏所罗曼的
that I somehow lack the wisdom of.
- 智慧吗 - 对
- Solo Man? - Yeah.
也有可能是大器晚成
Well, maybe it comes later.
- 可你通常都会问玛丽该怎么办 - 就是说说 - 对
- I mean you do usually ask Mary what to do. - I'm just saying. - Yeah.
这话太伤人了 希望你们能明白
This is very, very hurtful. I just want you all to know that.
正确发音是所罗门
And it's pronounced "Solomon."
没错
Oh.
还有什么发现 家人们
What else have we learned, fam?
就在那个神杖汲取了众神之力以后
Well, once the staff contained the powers of the gods,
人类巫师们接下来
the wizards apparently.
又用某种魔法结界把整个神界包围起来
encased the God Realm in some magical sphere.
将其永远封印 与魔法隔绝
sealing it away forever. Cut off from magic.
原来是这么回事
Oh, so that's what that was about.
可是他们现在好像没那么与世隔绝了
Yeah, I don't think that they are so cut off anymore.
今天早上
A bizarre.
希腊雅典上演了离奇又可怕的一幕
and gruesome scene unfolded in Athens, Greece this morning.
两个穿着类似古希腊铠甲的女人
Two women dressed in what appears to be ancient Greek…
那是巫师的神杖 怎么在那儿
Whoa, whoa, whoa, that's the wizard's staff. How did they get that?
那些雕像都是活人变的
So, all those statues used to be people.
我好奇的是 那个神杖
I'm wondering, how did the staff end up.
为什么在欧洲而且是希腊
in Europe, where Greece is at?
天哪 先生 抱歉拿了您的手杖
Oh, gee-whiz, mister, sorry I took your cane.
想要回去吗
You want it back?
我确实把它弄断以后扔掉了
I mean, I did break it in half and then throw it away.
说不定那就是这一切的缘由 对吧
So, that's probably where the journey started. You know?
什么
What?
什么什么 什么
What do you mean, "What?" What?
- 你把它扔那儿了 - 我们都在场
- You just left it there? - We were all there.
伙计们 我拿到神杖 给了你们超能力
Guys, I had a staff. I gave you all superpowers.
你们不用感谢
You're welcome, by the way.
后来我也只能把它断成两截
And then I had to break it in half so Sivana didn't do.
免得希瓦纳再做坏事 对吗
super bad-guy stuff with it, okay?
你弄断了神杖
You broke the staff,
也就打破了两个世界之间的屏障
meaning you broke the barrier between worlds.
我们现在刚刚知道
Which we now know.
而且我们还知道她们长什么样
We also now know what they look like.
- 等她们找来时 我们就知道是她们… - 三个
- So when they come to hunt us, we'll see those two coming a… - Three. What?
阿特拉斯有三个女儿
Atlas had three daughters.
卡吕普索
Kalypso,
赫斯佩拉
Hespera,
安西娅
Anthea.
Anne… thea.
听着 我不仅仅是超级英雄
You know, I'm not just a superhero.
也是最佳听众
I'm a super listener.
而且我能感觉到
And… I sense…
也许你对弗莱迪有好感
that you may have feelings for Freddy.
他什么时候回来
Just wanna know when he's coming back.
我不想让他受伤
Don't want him to get hurt.
好了 安
Oh, well, Anne…
我们选择不了自己会为谁心动
I mean, we can't choose the people we fall for.
什么
What?
我说的不是那种事
I'm not talking about that.
如果他现在出现 处境会很危险
If he shows up now, he's in serious danger.
瞧瞧我是谁 谁能危及我们
Whoa! Look who you're with. What could possibly be dangerous?
我们
Us.
好吧 我算看明白了
Okay. I see how it is.
比划比划吧
Let's dance.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
弗莱迪
Freddy?
弗莱迪 我不知道是你
Oh, Freddy, I, I didn't know.
我从没想过伤害你
I never meant for you to get hurt.
要受伤的人不是我
Oh, I'm not the one who's gonna get hurt.
沙赞
Shazam!
沙赞 沙赞
Shazam! Shazam.
- 这是怎么回事 - 老师
- What's going on up here? - Mis…
弗莱迪 你没事吧
Freddy, are you all right?
你快进去 进去 盖可老师 我没事
Get back inside. Just get back inside, Mr. Geckle. I'm okay.
你快进去
Go back inside.
你们是谁 学生家长吗
Who are you? Do you have kids here?
干什么 别动他
What are you doing? Don't hurt him.
我不会碰他的
I won't touch him.
我向你保证
You have my word.
[咒语]
盖可老师 她说什么 你怎么了
Mr. G. Wha… What did she say? What are you doing?
你干什么
What are you doing?
干什么 不不不 快停下 快停下 别走了
What are you… no, no, no! Stop, stop, stop! Wait, wait, wait!
不不 小心 别过去 不要 不不不 不
Hey, no, no, no! Wait, no, no,
不
no!
我忘了他们有多容易爆裂
I forgot how easily they burst.
你为什么要那样做
Why would you do that?
就像葡萄一样
Like grapes.
怎么回事
What the… Huh?
好了 孩子 告诉我们其他人在哪里
Now, child, tell us where to find the others.
不必了
No need.
剪掉他的翅膀 安西娅
Clip his wings, Anthea.
等等
Wait.
还有几个
There are more.
来得刚好 把他们干掉
Perfect. We take them all.
不 那不是来的目的
No. That's not why we're here.
先找生命之籽 放弃吧 姐姐
We're here for the seed of life. Yield, sister.
我们必须按计划行事
We stick to the plan we have.
父亲永远不会放弃
Father would never yield.
可是父亲已经死了
And Father is dead.
你得摆正自己的位置 妹妹
Now, you know your place, sister.
不然我就教教你
Or I will show it to you.
按我们的方式来 不是他们的
We do this our way, not theirs.
别轻举妄动
Make one move…
否则我拧断这孩子的脖子
and I will snap this child's neck.
哦 弗莱迪
Oh, Freddy.
比利 不
Billy, no!
[咒语]
比利 别过来
Billy, stay back!
她们要用神杖夺走我们的力量
They're using the staff to take our powers.
这是什么
What? What?
不 对不起
Sorry!
对不起 你 你快逃吧
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, just, just save yourself.
不 不行 同进同退 我们要团结
No, no, all or none. We stick together.
你会如愿的 因为你哪儿都去不了
And that you will because you cannot leave.
你们也尝尝被困在衰亡世界里是什么滋味
Let's see how you like being sealed off in a dying world.
不 不 不
No! No!
弗莱迪
Freddy!
从市区北部的市行大道
From City Line Avenue in the north.
到斯库尔基尔河的西岸 至卡波斯河
to the western shore of the Schuylkill River to Cobbs Creek.
莫名其妙地出现了一个穹顶状的不明屏障
The unidentified barrier appears to be in the shape of a dome.
切断了所有人进出城市的通道
with no one allowed into the city or out.
同时 有观点认为 这起奇异的魔法事件
with some suggesting this strange magical element.
有可能直接或者间接地
may be the doing, or undoing,
出自费城的废柴们的手笔
of the Philadelphia Fiascoes.
- 我的天 - 嘘
- Holy sh… - Shh!
我这儿刚要睡着
I'm trying to sleep.
这是逃离折磨的唯一途径
It is the only escape from the tortures here.
好吧 真惨
Okay. Bleak.
不对 等等
Wait a second.
海格的胡子 蝙蝠侠的声音
Hagrid beard, Batman voice.
你是巫师 那个巫师 天哪
You're the wizard. You're the wizard! Oh, my…
你又活了 比利跟我说过你
You're back! Billy told me all about you.
比利 你认识比利巴特森
Billy? You know Billy Batson?
比利巴特森是我最好的朋友
Billy Batson. Yeah, he's my best friend.
我是弗莱迪弗里曼 全能大队长
I'm… I'm Freddy Freeman, Captain Everypower.
我是说曾经是 这事很复杂 她很复杂
Well, used to be. It's complicated now. She… It's complicated.
比利那个蠢货把沙赞的力量传给了你
That halfwit Billy gave you the powers of Shazam?
对 他还说你变成了灰烬 可 可是你没有
Yeah, he did. And he said that you turned into ash, but, but didn't?
我把力量给了他 就不能留在我的法界了
Once I gave him the power, I could no longer remain in my realm.
被困在这间牢房里
But death would have been a luxury.
面对一败涂地的结局
compared to being trapped in this cell.
面对你 死亡变成了一种奢求
with the knowledge of my failure, and with you.
主要是因为你
Mostly with you.
比比利说话更爱挖苦人 可是没关系
A little more sarcastic than Billy said, but, hey, all good.
我们离开这儿吧
Let's just get out of here.
我们离开这儿吧 你想得美
"Let's just get out of here." Yeah, sure.
我不那样说话 无所谓
I sound nothing like that, but okay.
情况是这样
Here's what we've got, um…
一个阴阳怪气的暴脾气巫师
A cranky wizard with a cynical streak.
还有一个在魔法方面无所不知的早熟少年
and a precocious young man with an encyclopedic knowledge regarding magical shit.
那三姐妹绝对不可能困得住我们
There is no way these sisters are keeping us in here.
这些栏杆可能被施了魔法 你会什么咒语
These prison bars, they're probably enchanted! What spells do you know?
- 求你把嘴闭上 - 奥术专注你会吗
- Please, stop talking. - How about an arcane focus?
我连那是什么都不知道
I don't even know what that is.
行 那就做药水
Fine, then let's make a potion.
比如能获得巨人之力的药水或是缩小药水
Like a potion of, um, giant strength or diminution.
哦 气化形体 对
Oh! Gaseous form!
也许我们能像屁一样飘走
Yeah! Maybe we could float out of here like a fart.
我竟然把力量给了一群肆意挥霍的小屁孩
I gave my powers to children who squandered it.
我们俩会死在这儿 弗里比
We will die here, Freeby.
提醒一下 是弗莱迪 弗里比 你怎么…
It's Freddy, by the way."Freeby"? Where do you even…
你越早接受事实
The sooner you accept it,
就越能轻松面对
the easier it will be.
这是牙吗 这里有一颗牙
Is this a tooth? There's a tooth in here!
（自然之力 混沌之力）
“她们拥有自然之力 混沌之力
"Power of elements. Power of chaos.
而且还拥有轴心之力”
Power of axis."
这些全都是上古神力
These are primordial forces.
不知道我们该怎么才能与之对抗
I don't know how we fight powers like this.
我告诉你怎么对抗 谁的智慧来着
I tell you how we fight it. With the wisdom of…
- 所罗门 - 就是他
- Solomon. - Exactly.
不如我们来安排一场会面
We, we set up a meeting.
对 没错 告诉她们我们要谈判
Yeah, we tell 'em we want to negotiate.
提出用我们的力量换弗莱迪
Offer up our powers for Freddy.
然后趁机抓住她们其中的一个
But then we grab one of them.
那才是真正的筹码
and that's what we really use to trade!
如果她们窃取我们的力量呢
But what if they steal our powers?
不 不会的
No, they won't,
我们已经了解她们的路数了 懂吗
'cause we know how they work now. You know what I mean?
如果她们把神杖对准我们 那就快躲
If they just point that staff at us, we dodge.
躲避球
Like dodgeball.
伙计 我躲避球玩得很烂
Dude, I suck at dodgeball.
也许佩德罗不擅长躲避球
Well, maybe Pedro sucks at dodgeball,
超级佩德罗可不一定
but not Super Pedro.
不 超级佩德罗 躲避球也一样烂
No, Super Pedro also sucks at dodgeball.
好吧 听着 我们有五个人 她们只有三个
Fine. Listen, all I know is that there's five of us and three of them.
所以我认为 我们应该发出邀请
So I think we should send them a little invitation.
好的 据史蒂夫说
Okay.
这一摞纸都是有神奇魔力的羊皮纸
So, Steve says that this paper is a stack of magical parchment.
只要在魔法纸上写下留言
You write a message on the magical paper.
然后对它说出你想与之交谈的神的名字
and say the name of the god that you would like to talk to.
那么这张纸会折叠成…
and then the paper folds into a…
我的天哪 没错
Oh, my God, yes!
一只小小纸鸟 而且会飞向那个神
A paper bird. And it flies to the god.
还挺可爱的
Well, that's kinda cute.
嘿 那半神可以吗
Hey, what about demigods?
比如 比方说 神奇女侠
Uh, you know, like, Wonder Woman?
你觉得她现在能收到飞鸟传信吗
Do you think she's accepting bird letters right now?
这支笔耸肩了
Did the pen just shrug?
嘿 史蒂夫 我只能写给…
Hey, Steve, do I just dictate to…
（是的）
好的 我明白了 揉成团 好了
I do. Okay, cool, wad that up. All right.
写信
Letter…
写信 写一封信
Letter, writing a letter.
不是 不是 不是
No, no, no!
我随口说说而已 不是信的内容
I was just talking out loud. That's not a part of the letter.
还是揉成团
Wad that up, too.
也许可以试一试说出你的心里话
Maybe if you try speaking from the heart.
亲爱的阿特拉斯之女
"Dear daughters of Atlas,
暴力不是解决问题的办法
violence is not the answer."
孩子 如果说实话 我可以饶你一命
Child, I will spare your life if you're honest with me.
说实话
Honesty.
行 选这个话题 还真是够讽刺的
Yeah, wow, very, um, ironic subject choice.
其他的继承者
The other Champions…
他们也是像你一样的孩子吗
are they children like yourself?
具体什么样才算是个孩子
What even is a child?
我大概每星期都会刮胡子
I mean, I know I shave, like, every week-ish.
是或不是
Yes or no?
不是 答案是否定的 因为没有人
No. Your answer is no because nobody's stupid enough.
会愚蠢到把上古神力给一群小屁孩儿
to grant primordial god-like powers to a bunch of kids.
告诉我们名字
Give us their names.
继承者的名字吗
The names of the Champions?
有布雷特布雷耶 还有伯克布雷耶
Um, well, there's Brett Breyer, and, uh, Burke Breyer.
你们这样能记住吗
Are you guys taking this stuff in?
写下来 不用
Writing this down? No?
- 他们开一辆皮卡 - 他在说谎
- They drive a Dodge Ram. - He's lying.
那是你的超能力 不是我的
That's your superpower, not mine.
她说有个控制狂姐姐
And she thinks you're a total control freak.
就一个 可能是你
One of you. Probably you.
按住他
Hold him.
不要…
Don't…
怎么回事 什么东西 她要 她要干什么
What's happening? What is that? What's she doing?
小心混沌之力
Power of chaos.
那会侵入并且摧毁你的意识
It enters a man's mind and shatters it whole.
我的脑子乱七八糟的 行
Oh. My mind is already trash,
有本事你就试试
so I'd actually like to see you try.
因为没有人有胆量去应付我脑子里面的东西
Because nobody has the balls to handle what's inside my brain.
说出他们的名字
Say their names.
天命真女组合比你强多了
Destiny's Child did it better.
他比看起来要更强大
He is stronger than he looks.
- 说出他们的名字 - 停下来
- Say their names. - Stop!
比 比比比 比比比 比利
Billy…
巴巴 比 比利巴巴
Billy Bats…
巴特 比利巴
Billy B…
住手
Stop.
是继承者们来的信
This is from the Champions.
“亲爱的阿特拉斯之女
"Dear daughters of Atlas,
暴力不是解决问题的办法
violence is not the answer.
哦 这个开场白真不错 谢谢你 达拉
Oh, good first sentence. Thanks, Darla.
- 我们希望做一笔交易” - 什么
- We'd like to make a trade. - What?
“我们愿意放弃超能力 以此换回弗莱迪
We'll give up our powers if you give us Freddy,
加上毫发无损
add "unharmed".
免得让她们耍些小聪明 钻了空子
Otherwise, they're gonna monkey's-paw you.
真聪明 尤金
Smart, Eugene.
史蒂夫 加上毫发无损
Steve, add "unharmed".
然后写上此致敬礼
Then, like, "yours, trul…"
不对 换成敬上 祝好
No, "Sincerely, best".
干脆署名就写继承者们好了
Maybe just signed "The Champions".
还需要校对一遍吗
Should we proofread it?
不用了
Naw,
史蒂夫不会犯错的 它总是如实记录
Steve doesn't make mistakes, just writes what you say.
好极了 我感觉写得相当不错
Great. I feel good about this.
我觉得也是
Me, too.
你们有谁还想来一瓶电解质水吗
Anyone else want a Gatorade?
有红瓶的吗 ”
Do we have red?
电解质水是什么东西
What is this Gatorade?
是不是武器
Is it a weapon?
姐姐
Sister.
我们不需要再折磨他了吧 信你听到了
We need not torture him any longer. You heard the letter.
- 丢进深渊里 - 等等
- Throw them in the pit. - Wait.
他们是想做笔交易
They want to make a trade.
我们会赴约的 妹妹
And we will meet, sister.
但是人类并不值得信任
But humans are not to be trusted.
深渊只是名字可怕 其实很有趣 对吧
The pit is just a bad name for a fun place, right?
对吗
Right?
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
没有 感觉像个废物
No, just worthless.
- 可是你得站起来 - 为什么
- Well, you must get up. - For what?
我假装是超级英雄 只不过是…
All this pretending to be a superhero is just…
为了掩饰崩溃的内心
a way for me to pretend I'm not broken.
百感交集
Oh, feelings.
- 有个东西在动 - 对 我也看到了
- I see something moving. - Yeah, I see it, too.
见鬼
Oh, shit.
那是什么
What is that?
拉冬
Ladon.
阿特拉斯花园的守护者
The guardian of the Garden of Atlas.
跑
Run.
不行 我做不到
I can't. I can't!
别叫 别叫 没事 没事了
You're okay! You're okay.
感觉可不像没事
I don't feel okay at all.
那便是那条巨龙的力量
That's the power of the dragon.
它每个毛孔都散发着令人胆寒的东西
It emanates fear from every pore of its body.
拉冬的恐怖能麻痹任何凡人
Ladon's fear paralyzes any mortal,
这样就没人能靠近它守护的花园了
so that none can approach the garden it protects.
这个轴心之力 真酷 非常非常特别
Power of axis. Very cool, very, very rare.
安西娅
Anthea!
我得走了
I must go.
通往你们世界的大门就在迷宫的中心
The door back to your world is at the center of the labyrinth.
右转 左转 左转
Right, left, left.
再沿右侧墙壁走到中心
and then follow the right-hand wall to the center.
- 你能用得上 - 你怎么找到的
- You'll need this. - How did you find this?
你曾在你的世界保护我不被欺负
You once protected me from the bullies in your world,
弗莱迪弗里曼 在这儿换我保护你
Freddy Freeman. Now I've protected you in mine.
英雄
Hero.
有一说一 其实我并不需要你的保护
Well, to be fair, I didn't actually need your protection.
在你插手前
I was about to rearrange those boys'
我正要把他们的五脏六腑颠倒过来
internal organs when you stepped in.
但你并不知情 所以你确实非常勇敢
But you didn't know that, which does make you brave.
我勇敢是因为知道自己有超能力
I was just brave because I knew I had powers.
不 你最强大的力量其实是你自己
No, the most powerful thing about you is you.
你们俩真是太有爱了
How lovely for both of you.
女神 真的万分感谢 可是我们必须得…
Goddess, we thank you much, but we must get…
你们走吧 姐姐们不需要你们了
You should go. My sisters don't need you anymore.
她们现在只想要种籽
All they require now is the seed.
- 什么 你说种籽 - 没错
- The seed? - Yes.
种籽依然藏在她们神族无法触及的地方
Which remains hidden in a place unreachable by any of their kind.
我们走 杰夫 快点儿
Come, come, Jeff. Faster.
你叫我杰夫 她刚刚说了我的全名
You call me Jeff? She just said my entire name!
（萨姆城堡牛肉三明治）
你好 嗨 神 不行
Hi, God… No?
哟 低压老兄
Yo, Low Voltage.
你什么时候能弄走这个破穹顶
When you fixing this dome shit, man?
不 别担心 先生 我有办法
Oh, no, no, no, don't worry, sir. I have a plan.
- 真的 - 嗯
- Really? - Uh-huh.
可是你看起来只有三明治
'Cause look like all you got is a sandwich.
这些三明治吗 不 它们真的很重要
No, these sandwiches? No, these sandwiches are important.
- 这些都是谈事用的 - 才怪
- They're, they're for a meeting. - Yeah, sure,
三明治上校
Colonel Cheesesteak.
上校
Colonel?
乖乖 得好好起个名
Oh, boy, I really need a name.
你走路没声音啊
Quiet one, she is.
这能让我神不知鬼不觉地割开敌人的喉咙
I find it the most effective way to slit an enemy's throat.
真 那是…
Is that…
你是认真的 好吧
Oh, you're totally serious. Okay.
你看 事情是这样的
Right, so, look, here's the thing, um,
你很生气 一群巫师偷走了你们的神力
you're upset. A bunch of wizards came and stole your powers,
这事糟糕透顶 我完全理解你
which totally sucks balls, I totally get it.
但是
But,
我觉得你们把这件事情上升到私人恩怨了
I kind of feel like you're taking this all, like, really personally and,
可是 我们根本不认识吧 女士
like, I don't even know you, lady, right?
如果小偷半夜冲进你家
If thieves stormed your home in the night.
偷走了你所有的硬币逃之夭夭
and stole all your coin and then fled,
你理所应当会追上去 不是吗
you would naturally give chase, would you not?
假设在追捕的过程中
And say, in this pursuit the thieves.
小偷把钱掉到了地上
dropped the money on the ground.
结果你的邻居捡到 并且据为己有
and your neighbor picked it up and kept it.
下面 想象一下你丢的不是钱
Now, imagine it is not money,
而是你父亲的命脉根基
but the lifeblood of your father.
你母亲的最后一口呼吸
The last breath of your mother.
每一位神身上的力量
The power of all the gods,
以及神界上上下下的魔法都被人偷走了
the magic of the entire realm that was stolen.
可现在 这股魔法在你的身上流淌
And now this magic courses through you,
你这个人竟然恬不知耻地认为
and you have the gall.
那是你应得的东西
to believe that you deserve it?
这件事绝对是私人恩怨
This is very personal,
比利
Billy.
你真的很有震慑力
You are very menacing.
希望你知道这一点
I just want you to know that. Like, I really…
你的气场实在太强大了
I see the presence that you have,
可能很大程度上就是因为这个
and that goes a long way.
但是今天我到这里来主要是想谈谈妥协
But today, I really wanted to talk about compromise.
- 妥协绝对不可能 - 妥协绝对不可能
- There is no compromise. - There is no compromise.
我就知道你一定会那么说
I knew you were gonna say that.
萨鲁曼的智慧 别耍花招 懂吗
Wisdom of Saruman. Don't mess with me, okay?
交出弗莱迪 然后再把这个
Give us back Freddy, you take down this.
罩在天上的圆圆的魔法大碗弄走
sphere-y dome-y magic bowl thing.
这样一来 好吧
and then, you know,
我们就不用把你们都消灭掉了
we won't have to annihilate you into the ground.
这提议不错 我没开玩笑
It's a good offer. I'm being serious.
你很想扮演一个男子汉
You play the part of a man,
可是演技却很拙劣
but you do not play it well.
把超能力还给我们 孩子
Give us the powers, child.
全部超能力
All of them.
比利 你不是个领导者
You are no leader, Billy.
你只是个迷茫的小男孩儿
You are a lost boy.
却总是喜欢假装自己是个勇士
who likes to make-believe that he's a warrior.
好吧 听着 也许我没你阅历丰富
Okay, look. I might not have as much experience as you.
因为毕竟我不像你这么一把年纪
'cause I'm not, like, super old like you,
但是我想我也有一些你没有过的经历
but I think I have a few experiences that you don't have.
女士 我看过所有《速度与激情》电影
'Cause I've seen all of the Fast and the Furious movies, lady.
这么跟你说吧
And let me tell you something.
最重要的永远是家人们
It's all about family!
家人们 伙计们 那是信号
Family! Guys, that was the signal.
我们差不多练过十二次 谢谢
We practiced this, like, 12 times. Thank you.
你是不是忘记了我的家人们 女神
Forgot all about my family, didn't you, Goddess?
不 人类 是你忘记了我的家人
No, human. You forgot about mine.
- 来呀 - 快走 - 佩德罗
- Come on! - Let's go. - Pedro!
你在浪费我的时间 小子
You're wasting my time, boy.
厉害吧
Yeah.
她肯定没预见有这招
She sure didn't see that coming.
因为她根本没有去看眼科医生
because she didn't go to the eye doctor.
达拉 那是因为…
Uh, Darla, that was, 'cause…
那叫委婉语 是委婉的说法
A euphemism. That was a euphemism.
不
No!
我们已经夺回了你两位家人的超能力
We've taken the power from two in your family already.
现在又有两个要没命了 是为什么
And now two more must die, and for what?
为了你能继续玩打仗游戏吗
So you can keep playing soldier?
我的父亲是阿特拉斯
My father was Atlas.
是掌管毅力和力量的泰坦巨神
Titan god of stamina and strength.
也许他的魔法和神力在你的身上
His magic and power may course through you,
但是你永远都成为不了一个真正的神
but you will never be a true god.
是吗 那他会快速移动吗
Oh, yeah? Did your dad have superspeed?
没有
Nope!
- 没事吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Okay.
真好玩儿 快走吧
That was fun. Let's go.
（营业中 每周日 上午9：00-下午4：00）
（厕王有限责任公司）
快点儿 快走 快走
Come on. Come on, come on.
（员工通道）
大家快点儿 快走 快走
Hurry, everyone! Let's go, let's go.
干什么
What?
你还真以为
You thought you were just goin'
我们要挤进一个移动厕所里 对不对
into some regular porta-potty, didn't ya?
我现在好像还能闻到一点儿
Which I can somehow still smell.
- 对 没错 那个味散不去 真要命 - 是啊
- Yeah, yeah, it really sticks around. It's crazy, right? - Yeah.
就像渗到了空气里
Like, permeates the air.
无所谓了 总之欢迎来到永恒之岩
Doesn't matter. Anyway, welcome to the Rock of Eternity.
只有继承者们才可以通过任意一扇门
Only Champions can get in here, through any door.
到这里来
that we want.
我们几个能做到 你的妹妹们不行
Little thing that we can do that your sisters can't.
伙计们 这个就是我说的大获全胜 好吧
Guys, that's what I call a total success. Okay,
至少也算小有成就
maybe, like, a partial total win.
说了我躲避球很烂
Told you I suck at dodgeball.
是的 确实如此 可是 听着 佩德罗
Yeah, you do, yeah, but you know, look, Pedro,
我们每个人都有弱点 懂我的意思吗
we all have our weak spots. You know what I mean?
她的弱点
And hers…
就是缺乏战略思维
lack of strategic thinking.
该说正事了
Now for the real trade.
弗莱迪 还有神杖 换你的自由
Freddy and the staff, for your freedom.
还得把穹顶撤掉
And get rid of the dome.
没错 把穹顶撤掉
Oh, yeah. And get rid of the dome.
因为这座友爱之城变得有点潮乎乎的
'Cause the city of brotherly love is gettin' a little moist.
你可真会用词
Word choice, man.
得了吧 我一说出这个词马上就后悔了
Yeah, I regretted it as soon as it was coming out of my mouth.
那么说太…就只有那一个词
It's just one of those words…
我知道 可是
I know. I just…
“亲爱的阿特傻瓜拉斯的女儿们” 真伤人
"Dear daughters of Asshat-Las." Burn!
我灵光一现
I just came up with that.
记得加上一个破折号 这样才更明显 好
Make sure you put a dash in there, though, so it's really clear. Okay.
天哪 有史蒂夫检查语法和拼写真的太方便了
Man, it's so good having Steve cover grammar.
我听起来像个大聪明
and spelling and stuff, it makes me sound so much smarter.
好了
So…
“用兄弟换姐妹
"A brother for a sister, huh?
感觉怎么样
How's that feel?
还有 你们怎么会是亲姐妹呢
Also, how are you actually sisters,
因为你们的年龄差距
because the age difference.
实在过于明显 而且
is very noticeable, and.
有点令人不安 实话实说”
slightly upsetting, I'm not gonna lie."
虽然说我不是特别喜欢你
Even though I don't like you very much,
而且每个人都该享有人权
I believe everyone deserves human rights,
可是你不配吃草莓味的
but you don't deserve strawberry.
你只能吃黄色的
You only get yellow.
（基地）
她不见了
She's gone!
等等 什么
Wait, what?
（冷静区）
我就觉得我们抓她太容易了
I thought we brought her in too easily.
她是故意被抓的
She wanted to get caught.
我不太明白 她能跑哪儿去呢
I don't get it. Where would she even go?
坏了 其实早该料到
Well, this seemed inevitable.
好 我们彻底迷路了 谢了 笨蛋
Yep. We are so lost. Thanks, bozo.
我们并没有迷路 到底谁是巫师
We are not lost. Who's the wizard here?
这 这个我可说不好
I don't know.
你 你既不会咒语 也没有什么法器
You don't have any spells, no magical artifacts,
你对魔法一无所知 就只会…
you know nothing about magic, you're just…
- 你是巫师 - 谢谢 - 随便吧
- You're the wizard. - Thank you. - Whatever.
现在让我们看看你女朋友是否可以信任
Now let's see if that girlfriend of yours can be trusted.
回去
Get back, get back. Get back.
[咒语]
- 好 应该安全了 我们回家 - 等一等
- Okay, I think the coast is clear. Let's go home. - One moment.
你没看到她手里拿着什么吗
Did you not see what she was holding?
苹果而已 说不定她想吃水果 那有什么
It was an apple. She wanted a snack. What's the big deal?
那个就是金苹果 生命之树上结的
The golden apple. From the Tree of Life.
生命之树
From the Tree of Life.
等等 它不是在安全的地方吗
Oh, wait, hold up, didn't you say that was somewhere safe?
- 比利 - 比利 天哪
- Billy! - Billy. Gosh.
你要去哪儿
Where are you going now?
（没有氧气 仅限成人）
没有
Nope.
她没在那里
She's not in there.
不行 不 不 不
Nope. No, no, no.
那里绝对不行
That's a hard pass. That's a hard pass.
（危险 请勿入内）
比利 不用管那扇门
Yo, Billy, you don't gotta worry about that one.
里面是一个哪儿都去不了的迷宫
It's just a labyrinth that doesn't go anywhere.
就像古希腊的迷宫吗
Like an ancient Greek labyrinth?
伙计们
Guys…
厕所味
porta-potty.
赫斯佩拉
Hespera.
好了 姐姐
It's over, sisters.
现在我们可以种下种籽 重建神界了
Now we can plant the seed and restore our realm.
或者种在他们那里
Or we plant it in their realm.
那会毁了他们的世界
But that would destroy their world.
这只是以牙还牙
Just as they destroyed ours.
你是在说笑吧
You can't be serious.
不是
Yes.
不行 我们不是这么约定的
No. No, that's not what we agreed to.
哦 安西娅 你这小傻瓜
Anthea, you simpering bore.
她说得对 这一刻我们等太久了
She's right, we've spent ages waiting for this moment.
我们拿到了种籽 还有神杖和它的魔力
We have the seed. We have the staff and its powers.
我们不能为你的私欲而浪费这次机会
We are not squandering it for your personal satisfaction.
嘿 不行 应该我去 你别去
No, I should go, not you.
听着 我知道你的想法
Look, I know what you're thinking.
拄拐的孩子不是做贼的好材料
The kid with the crutch doesn't exactly sing "sneak thief."
可事实是
But here's the deal.
你走路膝盖嘎嘣响 真可怜 你听
Your knees crack like crazy when you walk. It's pathetic. See?
祝你好运 弗莱迪 谢谢
Fortune be with you, Freddy. Thank you.
你刚叫我什么
What did you just call me?
弗莱迪
Freddy.
弗莱迪弗里曼
Freddy Freeman.
没错 叫对了
That's it. You nailed it.
我们在另一边会合
I'll see you on the other side.
即使这样
Even if we did,
生命之树也无法在人界土壤中生长
the Tree of Life would not thrive in their soil.
它会搞破坏 会生出面目全非的…
It would despoil, it would disfigure into something…
怪物 人类都是怪物
Monstrous? That is what humans are.
把我们的怪物带到他们的世界
It is only fitting that we bring our monsters to their world.
以牙还牙 才是正确的选择
and do to them as they did to us.
我们说好要恢复双方的平衡
We agreed to restore balance.
报复会对平衡造成很大影响
and vengeance has great measure of weight on those scales.
安西娅 人类都很凶残 对同类也是
Anthea, humans are villains, even to themselves.
- 不 不全是 - 全是
- No, not all. - All.
妹妹 我认为你被愤怒冲昏了头脑
Sister, I fear your rage has gotten the better of you.
为什么
Why?
人类肆意破坏
Humans wreak havoc and devastation,
然后又祈求神灵赦免
then pray to the gods to absolve them.
他们祈求秩序与和平
They actually pray for order and peace.
却每次都会毁掉这两样东西
when all they do is dismantle it at every turn.
安西娅 你现在拿着苹果
Anthea, I want you to take the apple.
种到我们的花园里
and plant it in our garden.
你果然向着她
Of course you turn to her.
父亲一定会以你们为耻
Father would be ashamed of both of you.
这东西是哪儿来的
Where did that even come from?
嗨
Hi!
你向着她 赫斯佩拉
You favor her, Hespera,
结果她背叛了我们
and see how she betrays us.
- 送他上西天 姐姐 - 不要
- Deliver him to his proper fate, sister. - No!
杀了他
Kill him!
那是什么
What is that?
问得好 不知道
Great question. No idea.
但是骗到你了
But made you look.
比利
Billy!
你的拐杖
Your crutch!
沙赞
Shazam!
- 好 - 休想
- Yes! - No!
我们有很多话要聊
So, we have a lot to talk about.
卡吕普索 把神杖给我
Kalypso, hand me the staff.
你没资格用它
You are not fit to wield it.
比你有资格 你拿着它毫无作为
More fit than you. You had him in your hands, yet did nothing.
我们唯一的目的是为父亲报仇
Our sole purpose is to avenge our father,
结果每个人都软弱不堪
but everyone here has become weak.
拉冬 灭世者
Ladon, world-eater,
快快觉醒
rise from the pit!
- 快走 - 全能大队长 他要去哪儿
- Go, go, go! - Captain Everypower! Where's he going?
怎么…
What the…
维克多 维克多 醒醒
Victor? Victor, wake up.
- 你这女人 怎么了 - 妈妈
- Hello. Oh, God, woman. - What?
爸爸 赶紧走 赶紧离开这里
Dad. We gotta go! We gotta get out of here.
快点儿 快起床 对 现在就得走
We have to go right now!
很可笑是吗 我知道你们怎么看
This is funny, right? I know what this looks like.
不对 我也不知道你们怎么看 你们别慌
That's not true. I have no idea what this looks like. Just don't freak out.
- 你们来干什么 - 不 不 不
- What are you doing? - No, no, no.
- 别怕 - 我是玛丽 - 不 不 你们可千万别慌
- Don't be afraid. - I'm Mary. - No, no, no, you guys, don't panic.
冷静 听我们解释 这是我们的另一种形态
Calm down and listen to us explain. This is another form of us.
我让你们别慌 看着我 我是比利
I said don't freak out! Look at me, it's Billy.
罗莎 我是比利 好吗
Rosa, it's Billy, okay?
- 那是尤金和弗莱迪 那是达拉和玛丽 - 是我
- And that's Eugene, and that's Freddy… - It's me.
很明显 还有佩德罗 正常的佩德罗
That's Darla and that's Mary, obvi, and then Pedro, just normal Pedro.
各位 没时间隐瞒了好吗
Guys, this is no time for secrets, okay?
我们得告诉他们真相
We have to tell 'em the truth.
- 是我 我们是超级英雄 - 我出柜了
- We're superheroes. - I'm gay.
我们知道
Yeah, we know, bud.
- 真的 - 当然
- You knew? - Yeah.
当然
Yeah.
我是巫师
I'm the wizard.
这位是巫师 他是人称巫师的巫师
Oh, this is the wizard. He's a wizard who's called "the wizard."
好了 快穿衣服 快 快 快点儿
Okay, get dressed right now. Come on, hurry up.
穿好衣服
Put on these clothes.
太离谱了
This is so weird.
给 对 对
Yep, yep.
你们就是费城的废柴
You guys are the Philly Fiascoes?
我们绝不会承认那个愚蠢的绰号
Okay. This is in no way an acknowledgement of that stupid nickname.
但是 确实是我们 你们能快点吗
but, yes, that would be us. Now can you pick up the pace?
我们得走了 巨龙要来了
We have to go. The dragon is here!
巨龙
Dragon?
没事吧 没事 好
You okay? Okay.
我知道信息量有点大
I know this is a lot to take in,
但我保证稍后会解释
but I promise to explain it all later.
解释什么
Explain what?
孩子们是超级英雄 被众神追杀
That our kids are superheroes being hunted by Greek gods…
- 她们用龙毁了我们买的新房 - 对
- that used a dragon to destroy the house we just bought? - Yeah.
- 等等 你们买房了 - 对
- Wait, you bought the house? - Yeah.
快跑 快
Run! Go!
坏了
Oh, no.
蹲下
Get down.
行了 够了
Okay, that's it!
又来
Again?
弗莱迪
Freddy!
嘿 是想要它吗
Hey, hey! This is what you want, right?
好了 没事了
Come on, we're good.
现在安全了 快走
We're safe right now. Let's go. Let's go.
玛丽
Mary!
不
No.
嘿 你没事吧
Hey. Are you okay?
还好吗
You okay?
好了
All right.
巨龙跑哪儿去了
Now, where is this dragon?
（费城人队 市民银行球场）
这里适合做花园
Fitting place for a garden.
（树篱路 春园街）
（春园街）
（市中心 费城交响乐团 议会大厦）
（费城州立博物馆 会展中心区）
天哪 我要掉下去了
Oh, God, I'm slipping! Slipping!
（费城警察）
我的天哪
Holy moly.
我也没想到自己会这么说
You know, I never thought I'd say this about a dragon,
但巨龙现在只能算小麻烦
but it is the least of our problems right now.
- 你们的世界要完了 - 这不明摆着吗 神棍
- Your world will not survive this. - Yeah, no shit, Merlin!
他说得对
He's right.
安
Anne!
- 你还好吗 没受伤吧 - 我没事 我很好
- Are you okay? Are you hurt? - I'm okay, I'm fine.
在神界 这棵树
In the God Realm, this tree…
代表着美好
is a thing of beauty.
还有和平
Of peace.
它不适合在人界生长
It was not meant for the soil of this realm.
借播种人之手变成了怪物
and it's become monstrous by the hand that planted it.
她到底是哪一头的
Whose side is she on, anyway? Do you…
我得去说服赫斯佩拉
I must try to sway Hespera.
只有她能阻止卡吕普索
Only she can subdue our sister.
我会全力以赴 殊死一搏
I will give it my all, or die trying.
死 不行 我想一定能有办法让你不死
Die? No, I'm pretty sure we can come up with an alternative to dying.
弗莱迪宝贝儿 我准备好了
My sweet Freddy, I'm ready if need be.
我年纪很大了
I've lived a long life.
什么叫年纪很大
What are you talking about, "Lived a long life?"
我们同龄 你我都很年轻
We're the same age. You're young. We're young.
我已经六千多岁了
I'm over 6, 000 years old.
真会保养
You look great.
我们好像不该在这儿
Suddenly seems inappropriate.
是啊
Yeah.
不能让她死 她叫我宝贝儿
We can't let her die. She called me sweet!
我们得想想办法
We have to figure something out.
- 收回我的力量 - 不行 比利
- Take my powers back. - No, Billy!
不 不 不 嘿 收回我的力量
No, no, no. Hey, take my powers back.
你既然能给我 也肯定能收回
You gave 'em to me, so you can take 'em back, right?
我已经不是继承者了 你才是
I am no longer the champion. You are!
你以为我能解决问题 老兄
You think I know how to fix this, dude,
但我真的不会 好吗
but I really don't, okay?
我根本不认识那希腊三姐妹
I, I didn't even know who those Greek sisters were.
还得上网查 但你知道她们
I had to Google them. But you know who they are,
也知道该怎么办 你是对的
which means you know what to do. And you were right.
你选错人了 老兄
You picked the wrong champion, man.
所以我才老说同进同退
I mean, that's why I always say "all or none, " right?
因为我没了家人不行
Because without my family, I'm nothing.
我也不知道自己在干什么
And honestly, I have no idea what I'm doin'.
不
No.
你的脑子里没有一丁点智慧
You don't have a shred of wisdom in that brain of yours.
但你有睿智的心
But your heart is wise.
它非常清楚该做什么
And it knows exactly what must be done.
我用一千年时间寻找够格的继承人
I spent millennia searching for a worthy champion.
没人配得上我曾经与兄弟姐妹分享的力量
and no one was worthy of what I once shared with my brothers and sisters.
你分享力量的时候
But when you shared your powers,
完全没有犹豫
you did not hesitate.
你觉得人人都有资格
For you, everyone can be worthy.
只要有机会
if given a chance.
现在 去为家人而战
Now, go fight for your family.
为世界而战吧
Go fight for the world.
我当年没有选错人
I chose right when I chose you.
比利 比利 我们该怎么做 哥们
Billy? Billy, what are we gonna do, man?
按老办法来 弗莱迪
Same thing we always do, Freddy.
拯救该死的世界
Save the God darn world.
我现在去抢神杖
Now, I'm gonna go get that staff.
你们趁我对付巨龙的时候
and I need you to lure these things away.
引怪物离开体育场 好吗
from the stadium while I deal with the dragon, all right?
等等 比利
Wait, wait, wait, Billy, Billy.
能让我看看你吗
Can I just see you, before you go?
不是这个你
Not this version.
是真正的你 我的比利
You… You. My Billy.
沙赞
Shazam!
这就是房子老被闪电劈的原因
Is that why the house keeps getting struck by lightning?
我保证如果最后我没被龙吃掉的话
I promise after this if I don't get eaten by a dragon,
我不会强迫你留下我 好吗
I'm not gonna force you to keep me. Okay?
- 什么 - 我知道我快到年龄了
- What? - I know I age out soon.
比利
Billy.
我出色 善良 勇敢的儿子
My wonderful, kind, brave, son.
你永远是我们的孩子
You will never age out of your home.
永远
Never.
先帮我做件事
Now, do me a favor.
这是我发自内心的想法
and I mean this from the bottom of my heart,
去打败她们 好吗
go kick their ass, okay?
我爱你 妈妈
I love you, Mom.
我也爱你
Me too.
沙赞
Shazam!
我还真得适应一段时间
That's gonna take some getting used to.
大家快上战车 走 快走
Everybody to the battle wagon!
战车
The battle wagon?
我也想凑个热闹
Trying to get into the spirit of things.
（市民银行球场）
- 看看你对这些人做了什么 - 看到了
- Don't you see what you're doing to these people? - I do.
这是他们咎由自取
And what I see is just.
赫斯佩拉 你看这棵树
Hespera, look at this tree.
它枯萎了 这里不适合它
It is blighted. It is unnatural here.
我们发誓要重建神界 而不是毁掉人界
We made a vow to restore our realm, not destroy another.
神终于回应了他们
A god has answered their prayers at last.
他们没摆正自己的位置
They did not know their place,
我就提点了一下
so I am showing it to them.
你的语气像哈迪斯叔叔一样狂妄
Your fanatical tone echoes our uncle Hades.
不行 我要阻止你
No. I'm putting an end to this.
赫斯佩拉
Hespera.
不
No!
赫斯佩拉
Hespera.
既然你这么同情人类 那么
If your emotions rest with the humans so, Anne,
安 也许你应该做个人类
then perhaps you should be human.
天哪 救命 救救我们
Help, somebody! Somebody help! Somebody help!
怎么办 牛头怪太多了 根本撞不完
Okay, now what? There are only so many minotaurs I can run over with this van.
（弗莱迪弗里曼）
嘿 史蒂夫
Hey, Steve.
怪物害怕什么
What are monsters afraid of?
（万兽之王）
万兽之王 是狮子吗
"The king of beasts." Lions?
独角兽
Unicorns.
真的 我喜欢独角兽
Really? I love unicorns.
但独角兽不喜欢你
Yet, the unicorn does not love you.
- 各位 独角兽不存在 - 什么
- Guys, unicorns don't exist. - What?
天哪
Oh, my…
嗯 也许你说得有道理
I guess maybe it's not so crazy.
独角兽是兽界最可怕的生物
The unicorn is the most fearsome creature of its realm.
冷酷无情 和你故事书上的小马不一样
Ruthless and cruel, not like the ponies from your storybooks.
它们厌恶人类
They loathe humanity.
它们喜欢什么呢
Is there anything they do like?
（万兽之王）
“黑暗洞穴 仙果”
"Dark caverns. Ambrosia"?
仙果 那是神吃的甘露
Ambrosia. It's like the nectar of the gods.
应该很甜 像蜂蜜
It's supposed to be sweet, like honey.
- 我有主意了 走吧 - 等等 孩子
- I have an idea. Go, go! - Quick, quick.
两位 你们尽量去多救一些人
Guys, get as many of these people to safety as you can.
孩子们
Kids?
- 我们走 快点儿 弗莱迪 - 快 我们走
- Let's go. - Come on, let's go!
- 你呢 - 我跟他们去
- Wizard? - I'm going with them.
弗莱迪
Freddy?
安
Anne?
Anne! Anne!
我都快不知道该怎么当家长了
I am not entirely sure how to parent, here.
嘿 骑龙的
Hey! Khaleesi!
我实在太满意了 你感觉如何
Whoo! That was really satisfying. How was that for you?
好样的
Yeah.
我们爱你 霹雳咔嚓侠
We love you, Thundercrack.
你最棒了 惊奇队长
You're the best, Captain Marvel.
是啊 加油 高压老兄
Yeah, go, High Voltage!
你说什么 兄弟
Oh, wassup, bro?
其实是最大电压
It's Maximum Voltage actually,
我外号很多 我们还在讨论呢 所以
amongst other names. We're still kinda workshopping it, so…
你以为自己刀枪不入 你错了
You thought you were invulnerable. But, no.
魔法火焰 魔法可以杀死魔法
Magical fire. Magic can kill magic.
对对对对 魔法杀死魔法
Yeah, yeah, yeah, "Magic kills magic."
早想到了 女士
Way ahead of you, lady.
我就是着急 因为衣服头一次烧成这样
I'm just trippin' out because I've never seen my suit burn like this.
另外 别想在我的城里撒野
Also, nobody messes with my town!
听见没有
Know what I'm saying?
我打败了叛徒姐姐 一个神
I defeated my traitor sister. A god.
你以为我灭不了你
You think I won't destroy you?
神杖在吸收能量
The staff is absorbing it all.
像电池一样
Like a battery.
（卡特里托斯椒盐卷饼）
这就对了
That's right.
跑吧
Run!
（单行道 停车）
这是个馊主意
This is a terrible idea.
你不知道它们有多残暴 多野蛮
You don't understand the savagery, the barbarity.
糟糕
Oh, no.
你好
Hello.
住手
No.
没事的 过来
It's okay. Come here.
达拉
Darla…
没事的 乖乖
It's okay. Good girl.
小心
Whoa, watch out!
达拉
Darla!
尝尝彩虹糖吧
Taste the rainbow.
好吃吗
Good, isn't it?
这是眼下最像仙果的东西了
It's the closest to ambrosia we have.
真乖
Good girl.
彩虹糖还不够
We're gonna need more Skittles.
尝尝彩虹糖 混球
Taste the rainbow, motherfu…
不不不 女士 你不能死
No, no, no. Lady, lady, you can't die!
快点儿 比利 快点儿
Come on, Billy, come on!
能量 医疗能量
Powers, powers, powers.
医疗能量 不 让人起死回生的能量
Medical powers. No. How-to-fix-dead-people powers.
除颤
Clear?
- 有戏 再来 除颤 - 住手
- Whoa! Come on! One more time. Clear! - Stop!
住手 让我安心去冥界吧 拜托
Stop! Let me go to the Underworld in peace, please.
女士 听我说 听我说好吗
Oh, lady, lady, listen to me, okay?
我不想让任何人死
I don't want anyone else to die.
我的家人 安西娅 其他人
Not my family, not Anthea, not anyone,
我们可以救他们 都因为那棵树 是吗
and we can save them. This all came from the tree, right?
没准我能想办法连龙带树一起弄死
I might know a way to destroy the tree and the dragon all in one.
拉冬的力量太强了 孩子
Ladon's powers are too great, boy.
那如果我用大量闪电让神杖过载呢
Well, not if I can overload the staff with enough lightning.
炸弹
A bomb?
- 这样杀得死巨龙吗 - 不止
- Is that enough to kill the dragon? - And more.
你会把穹顶内部炸成平地
You would annihilate everything that's inside the dome.
那我还得求你一件事
Well, then I have one more favor to ask.
安
Anne! Anne!
Anne!
快跑 快跑
Go, go, go!
（费城特警）
快跑
Back away!
安
Anne!
拉冬 杀掉叛徒
Ladon, kill the traitor.
不可能
Impossible.
让他屈服
Bow him!
我不行了 弗莱迪 没有神力了
I lost it. Freddy, I can't.
失去力量的神还是神吗
What is a god without her power?
你身上最强大的力量其实
The most powerful thing about you.
是你自己
is you.
你教我的
You taught me that.
杀了他们
Kill them!
砰
Boom!
龙啊龙 你肯定失望透了
That must be super disappointing as a dragon.
假如你是条龙 你会飞 会喷火
Assuming that you are one. I mean, you fly, and you breathe fire,
身子却是木头的
but you're also made of wood which is a weird flex.
这可是严重的设计缺陷 没什么好吹的
and a serious design flaw, if I'm being honest.
弗莱迪 安西娅 别
Freddy, Anthea, don't!
骗到你了
Ah, made you look!
女士 又上当了
Oh, lady, that's twice.
这次我连着火的小提琴都没用
And I didn't even need a flaming violin that time.
想要神杖吗 过来拿呀
You want the staff? Come get it.
快 赫斯佩拉
Now, Hespera.
快呀 快呀
Now. Now.
[咒语]
不 不 不
No. No! No!
撤掉穹顶
Remove the dome.
只要我还有气
As long as I still breathe,
穹顶就在
the dome still stands.
我在另一个世界等着你 妹妹
Till I see you on the other side, sister.
比利
Billy!
- 快点儿出来 - 不行
- Get out of there. - I can't.
比利
Billy.
我必须这样做
I have to do this.
比利 你在干什么 你不应该在里面
Billy, what are you doing? You're not supposed to be in there.
我必须在
Yeah, I am.
我一直觉得自己没用 不配拥有这身力量
I used to think that I couldn't do anything right, that I didn't deserve my powers.
- 但我能做到一件事 - 不
- But there's something that I can do. - No.
我可以救你们
I can save all of you.
- 我们同进同退 - 只能这样
- But it's all or none! - Yeah.
我家人都能活下来 谁也不会受伤
All of my family gets to live and none of them gets hurt.
弗莱迪 我曾经是孤儿 你也知道
Freddy, I've never had a family. You know that.
我在乎过的人都离开了
Everybody I've ever cared about, they all left me.
我妈妈 我爸爸 所有人
My mom, my dad, everyone.
所以有了你们以后 我就得抓紧
So when I found you guys, I had to hang on.
我抓得太紧了
and I've been hanging on too tight.
不
No.
我应该让你去追梦
I should have let you do your own thing.
现在你可以飞了
Now it's time for you to fly.
那你呢
What about you?
我是全能小队长
I'm Captain Everypower Junior.
不要忘了
Don't you forget it.
做个了断吧
We end this now.
好 来吧
Yeah. We do.
加油 比利
Come on, Billy.
他能行 你能行 他能行 他能行 不
He's got this. We got this. He's got this. He's got this.
比利
Billy.
飞吧
Fly.
比利
Billy.
（费城人队）
不
No!
沙赞
Shazam!
比利
Billy.
一位真神 谁能想到
A true god, after all.
他成功了
He did it.
我们走
We must go.
比利
Billy?
Billy!
比利
比利 你在哪儿
Billy. Where are you?
比利
Billy!
Billy?
比利
Billy! Billy.
Billy! Billy!
比利
Billy!
老兄 醒醒 你成功了
Dude, wake up. You did it.
好了 你该醒了
Okay. You're supposed to wake up.
按照剧本 你应该醒过来 睁开眼微笑
It's the part where you wake up and open your eyes and laugh.
说你上当了 我真上当了
and you're supposed to say you got me, 'cause you got me.
老兄 别开玩笑了
Dude. Joke's over, man.
比利
Billy!
比利 拜托
Billy. Billy, come on.
弗莱迪
Freddy.
你怎么了
What did you do?
醒醒 比利
Wake up, Billy.
- 比利 - 他在这儿
- Billy? - He's over here!
比利
Billy.
你混蛋
You asshole!
我们同进同退 同进同退
We're a team! We're a team!
哦 比利
Oh, Billy.
比利
Billy.
哦 我的宝贝儿 不
Oh, my baby. No.
他是英雄
He was a hero.
既是英雄 也是神
He was a hero and a god.
他应该得到妥善安葬
And he should be laid to rest like one.
孩子
Hey, pal.
这里还能复原吗
Will this land ever come back?
神杖的魔力耗尽了
The staff is drained of magic.
只有神之火花才能修复它的力量
Only the spark of a god can restore its power.
可神已经走了
and there are no gods left.
还有一位
There is one.
什么
What?
僵尸
It's a zombie!
各位
Guys!
干什么
What the hell?
你们两分钟就把我埋了
You buried me? In what, like, two minutes?
哦 比利
Oh, Billy!
天哪 我好想你们
Hey. Oh, man. I missed you guys.
太好了
Hi. Hey.
我的天
Oh, my God.
嗨 为什么不告诉我…
Hi. Why didn't anybody tell…
嗨 抱歉 我刚才…
Hi. Sorry, sorry, I didn't, uh…
没看到你 我刚才 刚才…
I didn't see you there, I was, um, I was…
我刚才死了
I was dead at the time.
你收到飞鸟传信了
So, you, uh… you got my bird letter?
我…
Oh, I, uh…
你这里好像有东西
I think you've got something…
我的…哪儿
On my… Where…
什么
What?
一只蜘蛛
That's a spider.
抱歉 这样很恶心 而且也很尴尬
I'm sorry, that's disgusting. Also, that's really embarrassing.
是有点
Yes, it is.
但你做的事情很了不起
But it was an amazing thing you did.
你牺牲了自己
The sacrifice you made.
让这个世界重焕生机
You brought this world back to life.
也许这一次 神与人类能和平共处
Maybe this time, gods and humans can learn to live in peace.
是啊
Yeah.
好好运用宙斯的力量
Use the power of Zeus wisely.
保重 比利巴特森
Be well, Billy Batson.
虽然我身上流淌着你父亲的力量
Hey, you know, just because your father's power is surging through me,
但是我们没有血缘关系 是吧
that doesn't technically make us related, you know,
我还差五个月就18岁了 所以
and I'm gonna be 18 in, like, five months, so…
专心拯救世界吧 孩子
Stick to saving the world, kid.
对 那个 那好吧 行 再见
Yeah, you know, like, that's… Okay, cool. See ya.
我家男孩怎么都找老女人
What's with our boys and older women?
嘿
Hey.
谁想恢复超能力
Who wants their powers back?
能恢复吧
We can do that, right?
- 能 - 好 很好 好
- Yeah. - Yeah. Okay, good. Good, good, good.
- 我想修好房子 - 能修好吗
- I'd like our house back. - Can we do that?
- 开饭了 - 来了
- Dinner! - Coming.
谢谢你们遵守规则
Aw. Thank you for respecting the cross-stitch.
（禁止在室内变身）
安西娅
Anthea.
你想好怎么处理你们神界的事了吗
Have you decided what you're gonna do about that god realm of yours?
我打算在神界恢复期间休息一下
Well, actually I'm gonna take some time off while it heals.
和人类一起待一阵
Spend some time with the common folk.
了解你们的世界
Learn some about your world,
看看我们能不能互相学到东西
about how, maybe, we can learn from each other.
拥有智慧的第一标志
Number one sign of wisdom:
承认自己永远有东西要学
Admitting there's always more to learn.
我意识到了
I'm coming around to it.
我去开门
I got it.
各位 各位
Uh, guys? Guys!
是巫师
It's the wizard.
- 不是吧 什么 - 我的天
- Oh, my God! - No way!
是我
Yes.
- 你们快看 看看他 多帅 - 天哪 真有范
- Look at this guy! - Look at him, he's so handsome.
- 真时髦 - 你打扮得太精神了 - 好精神啊
- You pimpin' now, what is this? - You look amazing. - You look great!
我刚好在附近
Well, I was in the neighborhood.
想在走之前过来表达我的感激之情
and, um, I just wanted to express my gratitude before I go.
抱歉 门铃坏了
Sorry. Doorbell's broken.
实际上 家里东西都坏了
Actually, everything's broken.
也不是
Not everything.
你刚好在附近吗
You were just in the neighborhood?
好吧 我来拿神杖
Okay, I came for the staff.
也许会保管它一阵子
Perhaps I will hold onto it for now.
我还想在化成一堆灰烬之前
I also wanted to see your faces one last time.
最后见大家一面
before I turn into a pile of ash.
- 等等 什么 - 不
- Wait, what? - No!
我开玩笑的 我叫了优步
I am making a joke. I have an Uber waiting.
另外 我在石头堆和监狱里待了太久
And besides… I've been trapped in rocks and prisons for far too long.
该看看你们的世界了
It's time to see your world.
我很荣幸
It's been an honor,
很欣慰 看你们翱翔
a privilege, watching you all soar.
- 你这巫师还不赖 - 谢谢 杰夫
- You know, you're not such a bad wizard. - Thank you, Jeff.
没完了
It never ends.
对了
Also,
我的超级英雄叫什么
what's my superhero name?
你呀 叫沙赞
Your name is… Shazam.
- 他记得 - 是啊
- Of course. - Yeah.
肯定有更好的名字
I still think we can beat it.
（沙赞）
《雷霆沙赞2：众神之怒》
我脚疼 还有多远
My feet hurt. How much further?
你不到十秒前刚问过我一遍
About ten seconds less than the last time you asked me.
对不起 我就是觉得可以把车停近点
I'm sorry, I just feel like we could have parked a little bit closer.
他不知道我们要来 我不想吓到他
He doesn't know we're coming, and I didn't want to spook him.
“吓到他” 他是超级英雄 又不是鹿
"Spook him." He's a superhero, not a deer.
好啊 回去吧
All right, let's go.
然后你去告诉沃勒 虽然她认为
And then you can tell Waller that even though.
这个人可以成为团队新成员
she thinks this guy could be a good addition to the team,
但我们没有见到他
we never actually met him.
因为你穿了双很破的鞋
because you wore shitty walking shoes.
首先 这是靴子
Okay, first of all, they're boots,
另外它们不破 很新 就是还没穿合脚
and they're not shitty, they're new. I just haven't had a chance to break them in yet.
别说了
Shut up.
沃勒说这家伙和他们一样强大
Waller said this guy is as powerful as they come,
但有点不成熟
but a little immature.
好极了
Oh, great.
（普通无铅汽油）
（免费汽油 加油时请检查）
（自助服务 严禁吸烟 关闭发动机）
比利巴特森
Billy Batson.
干什么 我不是
Yeah? I mean, no.
我从没听过这个名字 不知道你说的是谁
I've never heard that name in my life. I don't know who you're talking about.
但我想见见他
But I'd like to meet that person.
因为他听起来很酷 很搞笑 很有才
'cause they sound super cool. And funny. And talented.
还帅得很离谱 痞帅痞帅的
And ridiculously handsome, but, like, in a dangerous way.
你这是在说什么
What the hell are you talking about?
别紧张 我们认识你
Relax. We know who you are.
怎么认识的
How?
这你就别管了
Don't worry about that.
你们是谁
Who are you guys?
这你也别管了
Don't worry about that either.
我们知道你的能耐 所以来向你发出邀请
Look, we've seen what you can do. And we're here to make you an offer.
你愿意加入正义…
How would you like to join the Justice…
愿意 我绝对愿意
Yes! A thousand times yes!
我的天哪 我做梦都想加入
Oh, my gosh! I've been dreaming about this!
也不全是 我一般会梦到神奇女侠 但…
Well, I mean, not this exactly. Like, normally, it's Wonder Woman in the dream, but…
呵
Ew.
行 还挺顺利
Well, that was easy.
欢迎加入正义协会
Welcome to the Justice Society.
好 太好了 等等 什么
Yeah! Aweso… Wait, what?
正义协会 和正义联盟不一样
The Justice Society? Is that different than the Justice League?
对 正义协会和正义联盟不是一回事
Yes. The Justice Society is different than the Justice League.
因为它们名字不一样
because of how words work.
我想加入神奇女侠的组织 是你们吧
I just want to be in the Wonder Woman group. So, that's you guys, right?
不是
No.
为什么对神奇女侠这么执着
Why are you so obsessed with Wonder Woman, dude?
他开玩笑吧
He's joking, right?
不是
No?
好吧 我走了
Okay. I'm out.
我鞋不舒服 就在这等着
I'm gonna wait here, 'cause of the shoes.
你能开车过来接我吗
Can you drive by and get me?
嘿 我就提点建设性的意见啊
Hey, just a little constructive criticism.
有两拨完全不同的超级英雄
It's pretty confusing that there are two separate groups.
这让人很困惑
of superheroes.
这两拨人完全不相干 但名字里都有正义
that are totally unaffiliated, but both have "Justice" in their name, you know.
我说 你们有没有考虑过重塑品牌
Like, have you guys ever thought about doing a rebranding of sorts?
因为 看 我随手在同义词词典上搜了搜
'Cause just a quick search on Thesaurus.com,
选择可多了 伙计
you got so many options, man.
比如权威协会 对
Like, "Authority Society." Eh?
信条协会 好傻 很像法律术语
Uh, uh, "Code Society." That's stupid. These are, like, legal terms.
复仇者协会
"The Avenger Society."
我很喜欢这个
I like that, for some reason.
《雷霆沙赞2：众神之怒》
好哇 好哇 博士
Well, well, Doctor.
又见面了
We meet again.
你到底跑哪儿去了
Where in the hell have you been?
要想实施完美计划 博士
To implement the perfect plan, Doctor,
就得耐心一点儿
one must have patience.
你什么意思
What are you talking about?
已经过了两年了
It's been two goddamn years!
没错 但时间不过是大脑的把戏
Yes. But what is time but a trick of the mind?
和无意义的尺度
A meaningless measure.
嘿 我现在57岁
Hey. I'm 57 years old.
困在混凝土盒子里
I'm stuck in a concrete box.
周围全是疯子
surrounded by lunatics.
等着一只虫子来实施含糊的计划
waiting for a worm to enact some, what, vague plan I've been told absolutely.
自己还不知情
nothing about?
我在路上花了很长时间 好吗
It takes me a very long time to get places, okay?
我没有腿 也没有翅膀
I do not have legs, I do not have wings,
只能无休无止地蠕动
I just slither around endlessly.
但快到头了
But not for long.
全都告诉我
Tell me everything.
我还有一件事要做
Just one more thing I need to do.
什么
What?
不
No!
哦 该死的
Oh, goddamn it!